<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Chill - Tag - Red David | Tech, Gaming, and Coding Blog</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/chill/</link>
        <description>Chill - Tag - Red David | Tech, Gaming, and Coding Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:02:17 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/chill/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Roundup: July. And June</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/july-roundup/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:02:17 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/july-roundup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/og/july-roundup.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Okay, hear me out, I am still procrastinating after watching hours TED Talks and YouTube videos on how to be productive and avoid wasting time doing senseless things. What&rsquo;s wrong? Do I have a lot on my mind or in my hands to keep me posting blogs? Can&rsquo;t be motivated by self-help books and videos? Am I still waiting for when &ldquo;it&rsquo;s too late&rdquo;? AARGH</p>
<p></p>
<p><br><br></p>
<h1 id="hunyo">Hunyo</h1>
<p>So my last post was June 12, I celebrated my 29th birthday on the 14th and got me self an Elgato HD60S+ to achieve better mobile gaming mirroring but that still, I can&rsquo;t keep my streaming schedule! AARGH (2)</p>
<p>I got the thingy not just to stream games but for future use - like recording &ldquo;How to use this app&rdquo; for YouTube or presentations, so it may be an expensive thing but I always think of them as investment for my app development journey.</p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Elgato HD60S&#43;</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Speaking of streaming, I started streaming on Twitch! Right now, I planned on playing Minecraft, Left 4 Dead 2, and Call of Duty: Mobile. Also, I will try to stream on MWFS schedule playing those games or variety. <a href="https://twitch.tv/RedDavidGG" target="_blank">Give me a follow</a> and get notified when I go live.</p>
<p>I will be using my <a href="https://fb.gg/RedDavidGG" target="_blank">Facebook Page</a> and <a href="https://discord.gg/rKnJb4J" target="_blank">Discord server</a> to post updates.</p>
<h3 id="stream-setup-mobile-gaming">Stream Setup (Mobile Gaming)</h3>
<p>As of this writing, I am lucky enough to have this setup for mobile game streaming:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://shp.ee/znd3exz" target="_blank">Apple iPhone 11</a></li>
<li><a href="https://shp.ee/ta83sar" target="_blank">Elgato HD60S+ Capture Card</a></li>
<li><a href="https://shp.ee/uw5zqsr" target="_blank">Audio-Technica ATR-2500X</a></li>
<li><a href="https://shp.ee/m3dktiz" target="_blank">SteelSeries Arctis 1</a></li>
</ul>
<br>
<p>Any more happened last week of June? Hmm. Yeah right, I released an update for RPN Radio app for both Android and iOS adding a call-to-action button to send the stations a message thru Facebook Messenger. This was after watching on Udemy that apps or any products always have a goal-in-mind - the stations should increase inquiries for advertisement or any other public service comments.</p>
<p>The app is still available for <strong>FREE</strong> on Google Play Store, Huawei App Store, and iOS App Store. I created this simple app landing page for the <a href="https://tunein.rpnradio.com/download" target="_blank">links.</a></p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Call-to-Action Button - RPN Radio App</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I also got to try the new <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/windows-11" target="_blank">Windows 11 Insider Preview</a> on a VM. Tested on my main machine but I can&rsquo;t risk the beta so I rolled back to Windows 10.</p>
<br>
<br>
<h1 id="hulyo">Hulyo</h1>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start the month with a sweet treat, homemade chocolates courtesy of my SO. Anyone interested? Hit the like on the Instagram post below for us to start selling them. 😊</p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Tomoegirl&#39;s Homemade Chocolates</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I got my second dose of Covid vaccine (Sinovac) on the 6th, thankfully there were no side-effects except for the body aches I got after NOT SLEEPING WELL! 🤦‍♂️</p>
<p>With work, I updated the <a href="https://rpnradio.com" target="_blank">RPN website</a> overall layout after migrating to a new hosting provider. And some minor updates to some if not all the online systems.</p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>RPN Radio Website</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<br>
<h2 id="rainy-vacay">Rainy Vacay</h2>
<p>After that, I decided to take a <del>short</del> long break to escape the <del>jungle</del> NCR Bubble by going home to Pangasinan. I am so longing to be with the family after 6+ months of not going home - I went home last December 2020 to spend the holidays.</p>
<p>I was so looking forward to at least visit a beach, see a sunset, feel the breeze of fresh air but UNLUCKILY the weather ahead was not well! I did not see the predictions that there will be a coming storm for the week. So the first few days were a bust, and I just stayed inside and chilled out with some beer.</p>
<p>The 20th was a holiday, and magically the weather was at least fine for us to go to Binmaley beach - don&rsquo;t worry, there were no crowds so we can be safe, I think? The sun was peeping through the clouds and by the afternoon, a mild rain poured. Together with relatives, we spend some time there swimming, singing, EATING, and drinking booze until it&rsquo;s time to go home.</p>
<p><figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Binmaley Beach</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Lumpiang Gulay</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<p>My other plans went down the drain as the weather became worse, Dagupan City was flooded (plus high tide) that light vehicles weren&rsquo;t able to pass. Sadly, I can&rsquo;t meet my <del>only</del> city friends. There&rsquo;s still next time right? Right?</p>
<p>I decided to extend my stay but continued checking some online responsibilities just to make sure they are still up even I&rsquo;m not present in the office - though I failed to join our online meetings.</p>
<p>We also went to our grandfather&rsquo;s brother to celebrate his 70th birthday. Then we spent some time (and over pizza) with my cousin to talk about tech and stuff.</p>
<p><figure>
</figure>

<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Selfie with Lolo and Cousin &#43; Damaged Foods 🤣</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>
</p>
<br>
<p>Oh, I also got a haircut (question mark).</p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <h4>Haircut?</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<br>
<p>That&rsquo;s it for this blog post, thanks for reading! (the rain pours while I write this).</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
