<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>iPhone - Tag - Red David | Tech, Gaming, and Coding Blog</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/iphone/</link>
        <description>iPhone - Tag - Red David | Tech, Gaming, and Coding Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 03:22:25 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/iphone/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>(Updated) RPN News Mobile App Released</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpn-news-released/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 03:22:25 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpn-news-released/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpn-news.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="update">Update</h1>
<p>The app is now available for iPhones. See the <a href="#download-here">download section</a> below.</p>
<hr >
<p>It&rsquo;s been a while again since my last post but there were no significant updates lately - besides another week-long vacation. So let me introduce this new mobile app from RPN that I developed and releasing now.</p>
<h1 id="delays">Delays</h1>
<p>The app had a working beta for Android devices for awhile now with bare experience and a better update has been in the works. I took the time to work out the database functions, UI and UX, and some other features (mobile ads, and customized links).</p>
<p>I apologize for the delay but I just made sure these features are working for production.</p>
<h1 id="app-details">App Details</h1>
<p>Most brands nowadays accompany their line of business with a mobile app, beside the <a href="https://tunein.rpnradio.com/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN Radio app</a> which was released so much earlier, I am now finally be able to bring news mobile app for Android devices, and iPhones.</p>
<p>Right now, the app is a feed for the provincial news as visible on <a href="https://rpnradio.com/category/provincial-news/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN website</a>. The news are gathered by our provincial/regional news stations that you can read from the website or from the app - for much easier reading and sharing.</p>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<p>It took too long to release the app that the version is now at 2.1. Below are screenshots (store previews for iPhone and Android).</p>
<style>

div#gallery-rpn-news {
   display: flex;
    flex-wrap: wrap;
    justify-content: center;
}

div#gallery-rpn-news a {
  width: 20%;
  margin: 2px;
}

</style>
<div id="gallery-rpn-news">
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-1.png" title="News feed (iPhone)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-1.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-2.png" title="News details (iPhone)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-2.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-3.png" title="About page (iPhone)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-3.png">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div id="gallery-rpn-news">
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-1.png" title="News feed (Android)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-1.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-2.png" title="News details (Android)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-2.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-3.png" title="About page (Android)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-3.png">
        
    </a>
</div>
<h1 id="download-here">Download Here</h1>
<p>The app is available now on the Google Play Store: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.news&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN News - Apps on Google Play</a></p>
<p>Update: Download for iPhone here: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/app/id1590143546" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN News on the App Store</a></p>
<p>As for Huawei devices (App Gallery) <del>and iPhone App Store</del>, the app is still under review for each platform. Will add the links as soon as they&rsquo;re approved.</p>
<h1 id="whats-next">What&rsquo;s Next</h1>
<p>Here are the milestones I am looking forward to bring:</p>
<h3 id="milestone-22">Milestone 2.2+</h3>
<ul>
<li>News Filter (by Station or tags)</li>
<li>Search</li>
<li>National and International news (courtesy of BusinessMirror news)</li>
<li>Customizable fonts</li>
<li>Read aloud</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="milestone-30">Milestone 3.0</h3>
<ul>
<li>Integrate stations' live videos (YouTube)</li>
<li>Integrate stations' VODs (video-on-demand)</li>
</ul>
<p>As always, you can follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/reddvid" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a> for mini updates.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>My Top Apps for Windows and iPhone</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/my-top-windows-and-mobile-apps/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:45:35 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/my-top-windows-and-mobile-apps/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/og/apps.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>As you may know by now, I am an electronics engineer but currently and mostly doing IT stuff and some casual gaming. I can also describe myself as an on-a-budget tech enthusiast - I buy top-tier pc/laptop upgrades after some time since their release or when it&rsquo;s affordable enough; like when I went for 1TB Samsung 970 EVO just to hold the apps, games, and files that I leave after testing them out.</p>
<p>Having said that, I sometimes stumble upon bad or corrupted files, deleted some system files, OR EVEN installing Windows sh*ttiest Insider builds. But I seldom hold myself back reverting or reinstalling Windows to clean everything up.</p>
<h2 id="cloud-works">Cloud works</h2>
<p>I trust the cloud, at least with Microsoft&rsquo;s OneDrive service. I have a 1TB subscription with them to hold my most important files (like assets for this website, etc.) and pictures. I also always keep in hand a Windows installer on a USB stick. With all the files are backed up I simply begin reformatting it and reinstall apps/softwares starting with these:</p>
<h1 id="windows-apps">Windows Apps</h1>
<p>This list may or may not be in order.</p>
<h2 id="avast-driver-updater">Avast Driver Updater</h2>
<p>Since Windows 10, the OS also installs drivers but I make sure they are updated using this software. It has a free trial and it works just fine. At this time, I also install graphics drivers (AMD Radeon Software or NVidia GeForce Experience).</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://www.avast.com/en-ph/driver-updater#pc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Avast Driver Updater &amp; Scanner</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="microsoft-office">Microsoft Office</h2>
<p>My subscription also contains a license to use full desktop version of Microsoft Office so it&rsquo;s a win-win for me since this is an important skill? personally and for work.</p>
<p><strong>Product link: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/CFQ7TTC0K5BF" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Office 365 Personal</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="steam">Steam</h2>
<p>Additionally, I don&rsquo;t store my games to where my OS is installed. Steam and most game platforms allows us to locate game files, so I don&rsquo;t have to redownload hundreds of GB game files.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://store.steampowered.com/about/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Steam</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="bitwarden">Bitwarden</h2>
<p>Ever since I experienced being hacked, I immediately started using a password manager/generator to make my passwords not the same - YES what a shame.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://bitwarden.com/download/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bitwarden</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="winrar">WinRAR</h2>
<p>Compress and extract files and folders with unlimited 40 day trial.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://www.win-rar.com/download.html?&amp;L=0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">WinRAR</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="spotify">Spotify</h2>
<p>Even though the lack of lossless audio format, Spotify is my go-to music service. Unless it came preinstalled with Windows.</p>
<p><strong>Download links: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9NCBCSZSJRSB" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spotify (Microsoft Store)</a> | <a href="https://www.spotify.com/kw-en/download/windows/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Spotify (.exe setup)</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="voicemeeter-banana">VoiceMeeter Banana</h2>
<p>One of the most useful audio mixer I use. I allows to mix and manage audio inputs and outputs to use for other communication apps.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://vb-audio.com/Voicemeeter/banana.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">VoiceMeeter Banana</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="visual-studio-code">Visual Studio Code</h2>
<p>I use this as code editor for Flutter/Dart mobile development and other source codes like this blog.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Visual Studio Code</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="visual-studio">Visual Studio</h2>
<p>The full IDE software for various development cases. I mainly use it for Windows app development as I haven&rsquo;t got into webapps as of now. I code and create apps using WinForms, WPF, and UWP (WinUI). I also tried Xamarin.Forms but I moved onto Flutter for cross-platform mobile app development.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/downloads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Visual Studio</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="obs-studio">OBS Studio</h2>
<p>I used this for streaming, recording and virtual camera purposes. I now use OBS instead of XSplit. The software is FREE and much lightweight. It also has features and other free plugins made by the community.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://obsproject.com/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OBS Studio</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="figma">Figma</h2>
<p>This free app is browser-based but can also be downloaded as a desktop app. It was made for designers to build UI/UX interfaces - which I sometimes do when making apps. I also use this to make a quick and simple logos and other graphics.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://www.figma.com/downloads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Figma Desktop</a></strong></p>
<p> 
 
 </p>
<p>Now on to mobile apps. I switched to iPhone nearly a year ago because of the hardware-and-software stability (in my opinion) and the support does not end after 2 or 3 years, unlike Android. So resetting my device (after a really really bad beta software) isn&rsquo;t that much of a hassle because of iCloud backups.</p>
<h1 id="mobile-apps">Mobile Apps</h1>
<p>Here are my top apps that I use on a daily basis. I will not put the specific store page instead I will link to their website for mobile downloads (if available). I&rsquo;ll list the apps I use on both platforms (PC and Mobile)</p>
<h2 id="spotify-1">Spotify</h2>
<h2 id="bitwarden-1">Bitwarden</h2>
<h3 id="steam-mobile">Steam Mobile</h3>
<h2 id="microsoft-office-outlook-and-onedrive">Microsoft Office, Outlook, and OneDrive</h2>
<p>I put them together here since they are not in a suite but the new Office app user-wise deprecated the standalone Word, Excel, and PowerPoint apps since you can view and edit your documents in one app.</p>
<p><strong>Download links: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-ww/microsoft-365/mobile" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Office Mobile App</a> | <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/outlook-mobile-for-android-and-ios" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Outlook Mobile</a> | <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/onedrive/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OneDrive Mobile App</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="twitter">Twitter</h2>
<p>Where I get updated to what&rsquo;s happening. I only follow niche and some well-known &ldquo;wholesome and awesome&rdquo; Twitter users.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://twitter.com/settings/download?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="facebook-messenger">Facebook Messenger</h2>
<p>Yup, most family members and friends are into messenger chats so that&rsquo;s no escaping Facebook.</p>
<h2 id="gcash">GCash</h2>
<p>Globe Telecom&rsquo;s virtual wallet now available for all networks.</p>
<h2 id="youtube-and-reddit">YouTube and Reddit</h2>
<p>My other ways to consume content.</p>
<h2 id="microsoft-edge">Microsoft Edge</h2>
<p>Despite the sync being subpar to Google Chrome, I prefer this one as my main browser on my iPhone.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/edge#platform" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Microsoft Edge Web Browser</a></strong></p>
<h2 id="shopee">Shopee</h2>
<p>Every once in a while (trust me 🤣) we just want to shop online. I recently deleted my Lazada account because it annoyed me so much with their shenanigans - which I am not really sure.</p>
<p><strong>Download link: <a href="https://shp.ee/x6uyiut" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Shopee PH</a></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>So far these are my <em>top</em> apps that I use on my mobile phone. Let me know what&rsquo;s your most used apps!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Get RPN Radio for iOS</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-for-ios/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:50:15 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-for-ios/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/og/rpnradio-appstore.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>After more than 3 months of processing Apple Developer Program&rsquo;s requirements, the app is here for iPhones!</p>
<p>This is the very same version we release for the Android counterpart (<a href="https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/">read the details on this blog post</a>). Ads are disabled for now as I am still fixing things with the release of iOS 14.7</p>
<br>
<figure class="image">



<figcaption>App Screenshots</figcaption>
</figure>
<br>
<h1 id="roadmap">Roadmap</h1>
<p>The app is set to receive further updates, especially with station details. THe list below shows the top priority updates:</p>
<ul>
<li>Detailed station page (operating hours, location, and contact numbers)</li>
<li>Better player view</li>
</ul>
<br>
<h1 id="downloads">Downloads</h1>
<p>The app is FREE TO DOWNLOAD here:</p>
<p><a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/rpn-radio/id1571699396?itsct=apps_box_badge&amp;itscg=30200" style="display: inline-block; overflow: hidden; border-radius: 13px; width: 250px; height: 83px;"></a></p>
<figure class="image">

</figure>
<br/>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
