<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Red David Blog</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Red David Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:40:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing for Apple Soon</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/developing-for-apple-soon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:40:14 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/developing-for-apple-soon/</guid>
      <description>Apple User -&amp;gt; Me Yes, I gave in to use an Apple device. Well, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried an iPhone XS before, and I must admit, having a device with software dedicated to its hardware is chef&amp;rsquo;s kiss. That&amp;rsquo;s what I liked about Apple, the hardware and software work along each other, and like most people, the price-tag for their phones held me back until December.
I loaned for an iPhone 11 since the iPhone 12 is expensive and I like the 11&amp;rsquo;s grip instead of the sharp edges of the new design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZIP Code PH for Android gets Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:17:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>The Pandemic and Night Owls My app, ZIP Code PH, has been available on Google Play Store for more than a year now and because of the pandemic, more and more people are staying at home and are mostly night-owls.
And app and software developers are now giving their projects dark mode - not just to follow accessibility standards but offer an option for people to reduce or avoid eye strain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:25:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</guid>
      <description>This should just be a short post to promote and showcase this Android app I developed for my job.
AM Radio in your Pocket Choose from RPN&amp;rsquo;s (Radio Philippines Network) 12 regional AM stations to tune into. Just connect to the internet and be updated to the latest news, talks, and enjoy some old and new tunes.
Development I tried making this app using Xamarin.Forms but the new Android implementation of the media notification sucked a** that I made the app in pure Android Java code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Review</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/2020-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 13:27:12 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/2020-review/</guid>
      <description>Huh, who knew? That we can get through the sh*tty year that is 2020. 🤔 And for last time (and maybe first?), let&amp;rsquo;s take a look back to what happened with Red David&amp;rsquo;s life in last year (SPOILER: not so much, like most of us I guess).
January Puerto Galera, 2nd week New Year, New Decade! We expected a lot in 2020 coming from 2019. It started out pretty much a normal month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/links/</guid>
      <description>@reddvid
ul#list {list-style-type: none; text-align: center;padding: 0;}#listli {margin: 12px 20px !important;background: rgba(200, 200, 200, 0.3);border: 2px solid transparent;box-shadow: 1px 1px 5px rgba(100, 100, 100, 0.5);}#listli:hover {background: rgba(200, 200, 200, 0.2);border: 2px solid #56B2D4;}#listlia{display: block;width: 100%;height: 100%;font-size: 1.0rem;padding: 10px 0;}#listlia:hover {color: #56B2D4;}Help me reach 1K Followers on Facebook Gaming (need 56 more)ZIP Code PH for AndroidZIP Code PH for Windows 10RPN Radio for AndroidRPN News &amp; Radio for Windows 10Windows 10 AppsBuy me a coffee beerdocument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally! Logitech C922</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:17:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</guid>
      <description>Yoo! I finally got the C922 PRO HD Webcam from Logitech after wishing having it for years.
Honestly, I bought the camera in a slightly higher price due to the model being out of stock in major stores and just got from a &amp;ldquo;hoarder&amp;rdquo; in Facebook marketplace. :) Harsh but true.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get into my short blog/review/impression about this industry-standard in semi-professional streaming.
Wait You might ask, why only now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Keeb in Town</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 19:56:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple review and unboxing post for my newly bought keyboard today. It is the Tecware Phantom Elite TKL with Gateron brown switches. I am using it to write this post.
I have used a number of mechanical keyboards in the past, the first one was an Aula one with Outemu blues. Then a TKL with blue Gateron switches, I forgot the brand, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Chinese. And my slightly premium keyboards, the Logitech G403 and the G810.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZIP Code PH Gets Refreshed UI</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 22:02:34 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</guid>
      <description>Over these past few months, I have been checking on some fluent design concepts and app updates over Twitter and other design sites like, Dribbble, Behance, and even Medium. Also, I have been busy gaming and doing some reading on my spare time that I missed coding and updating some of my apps.
Then one time, I just found the urge to update it after seeing Michael West&amp;rsquo;s concept layouts over Dribbble.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Phone Tray V2</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 21:18:31 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</guid>
      <description>Your Phone Tray UWP app just got updated.
Version 2.0 brings few UI changes, some improvements and a breaking change.
Improvements To improve the app, I updated the tray icon context menu to show that it should be running on Startup (see Task Manager Start up) You can also see a new menu item Enable Ctrl+Y Hotkey. If enabled, the app silently picks up the Ctrl+Y shortcut to open Your Phone app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech G304 Review</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/g304-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 23:42:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/g304-review/</guid>
      <description>So this is my short and honest review of the G304 wireless mouse.
As I mentioned on my previous blog post here, this is my 4th mouse and my first gaming? wireless mouse. I ordered it online from DataBlitz for $39, and was delivered quickly in 2 days.
What&amp;rsquo;s in the box? The box contains the wireless mouse itself, the usual manuals, Logitech Gaming promo leaflet, a blue G logo sticker, a Duracell AA battery, and a USB extension cord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of my Logitech Mice</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/</guid>
      <description>Why do (or did) I own at least 5 of Logitech G mice despite the &amp;ldquo;double-clicking&amp;rdquo; issues about them? As an ECE, I knew that some percentage of any electronics produced out there do have flaws - and this is not an excuse for their price - but in the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; world, these things can happen. Also, when looking at r/mechanicalkeyboards they combo their awesome keebs with a Logitech mouse despite them hating on Romer-G&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying at Home During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/staying-at-home-during-covid19-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 01:28:20 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/staying-at-home-during-covid19-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>When the sudden rise of Covid-19 cases here in the Philippines, the government was urged to implement a community quarantine - which was a lockdown - public transportation is suspended, non-essential businesses must be closed or simply everyone should stay at home.
But working on a media and broadcasting field, yet being the transmitter engineers, we can&amp;rsquo;t help but think: Uhm, how about us?
Unfortunately, it took almost 2 days to formulize measures for us; don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, we wanted to be safe, but being the essential skeletal personnel in the operations of news source, and in my own opinion, we had to keep the broadcast on-air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebuilding Website with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/rebuilding-website-to-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 21:43:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/rebuilding-website-to-hugo/</guid>
      <description>It was early 2019, I think when I accidentally deleted my Wordpress database that contains at least 20 posts. Sad right? After that sad moment, I tried to repost everything using Hugo, a static website builder, but found that it was too complicated - with YAML, some .scss, layouts, etc.
So I gave up and made a basic website with just HTML, CSS, and JS files. It was ok for me, just having a landing page for my apps, other works and a short bio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 14:37:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my portfolioElectronics Engineer One of my greatest achievement in life, so far, is being a registered Electronics (and Communications) Engineer in the Philippines.
For almost 7 years in the field, below are some notable contributions to the companies I have worked and am working for:
 IP radio installations as Studio-to-Transmitter Links Minor (home and office) networking IT configurations Web and digital system administration  Software Developer Self-taught developer; apps for Windows Phone then, Windows 10 and Android.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/about/</guid>
      <description>--About MeHi! I am David. I am an electronics engineer and a software programmer.
I work in broadcast field since 2014. I code and develop apps on my rest days.
I manage and admin website and other digital media (e.g. live stream, social media, cPanel).
I am also an experienced object-oriented programming using C#. I also happen to know XAML, SQL, and Git. I use Visual Studio, VS Code, and Illustrator/Figma to design app logos, UI mockups, and promo images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy for Red David Apps</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/</guid>
      <description>We built the suite of apps for Windows (UWP, WinForms, and/or WPF) as a commercial. These services were provided by Red David and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform website visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use our services.
If you choose to use any of our services, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Got Myself a New Laptop</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/new-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 16:30:40 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-laptop/</guid>
      <description>Last February 15, I got myself a new Acer laptop. It is an Acer Nitro 5 laptop sporting an AMD Ryzen 3550H with RX560X Graphics. This makes my 3rd Acer laptop in a span of 8+ years and my first ever AMD on a laptop (had an AMD Athlon X2 PC before).
This laptop costs Php34,999 and we could not find a promo since every store follows the retail price. Although, the laptop was on promo with having an included a single stick of 8GB DDR4 memory (upgraded from 4GB), 128GB SSD (m.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPN Android App</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 03:02:48 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/</guid>
      <description>Hey hey, recently I branched out my C# and apps knowledge to create and actually port or make versions of my UWP apps to Android using Xamarin Forms.
Finally opt-in and registered to Google Play platform and chose RPN News &amp;amp; Radio to the Store as the first app (under my registered dev name) to become publicly available.
Obviously, this is unofficial and not backed by my employers. I believe having this in the store is essential to expand the platforms reached by RPN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RF Tools Gets Multi-Window Support</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/rftools-gets-multi-window-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 15:47:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/rftools-gets-multi-window-support/</guid>
      <description>UWP SDK recently released a new support for Multi-windowing.
Then I though of which of my apps should I implement this with, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing better than RF Tools, a calculator app for engineers and enthusiasts of radio frequency.
This should improve the user&amp;rsquo;s experience by doing multiple calculations visible at once; to compare and serve as a history.
You can download the app here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPN News &amp; Radio Gets a New UI</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/new-ui-rpnradio/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:28:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-ui-rpnradio/</guid>
      <description>A quite small update to fix and improve the overall UI of the app. Adding some fluent design, new font and smoother experience.
You can download RPN News &amp;amp; Radio for Windows 10 app here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story of Self-taught Coding</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/self-taught-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:22:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/self-taught-coding/</guid>
      <description>Started coding using VB.Net and Forms for our final year thesis (which programming was NOT a major). Then while gearing up for board exams, learnt to code and design for Windows Phone 7.5/7.8/8 using XAML, C# &amp;amp; Silverlight.
Then came Windows 8.1 and WP8.1 on the Univeral App Shared codes, but didn&amp;rsquo;t dive that deep because of some weird Windows 8.1 windowing and such.
Finally W10 and UWP, still slowly learning and managed to improve my coding skills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
