<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Red David</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/</link>
        <description>Electronics Engineer, Gamer and Streamer. Bloggin about technology, coding and software development, and music.</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:40:14 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Developing for Apple Soon</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/developing-for-apple-soon/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:40:14 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/developing-for-apple-soon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="apple-user---me">Apple User -&gt; Me</h1>
<p>Yes, I gave in to use an Apple device. Well, I&rsquo;ve tried an iPhone XS before, and I must admit, having a device with software dedicated to its hardware is chef&rsquo;s kiss. That&rsquo;s what I liked about Apple, the hardware and software work along each other, and like most people, the price-tag for their phones held me back until December.</p>
<p>I <em>loaned</em> for an iPhone 11 since the iPhone 12 is expensive and I like the 11&rsquo;s grip instead of the sharp edges of the new design. I got a yellow one since the black sold out. Then I realized black, though very simple, is such a generic color that it doesn&rsquo;t stand out as a phone&rsquo;s color and I&rsquo;ve had too many black phones before.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Yellow iPhone 11</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="developing-for-ios-soon">Developing for iOS soon</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;m excited to learn new things and finally applying the cross-platform capabilities of <a href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/apps/xamarin/xamarin-forms">Xamarin.Forms</a> which I have used in some of my Android apps and it&rsquo;s <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/tour-of-csharp/">C#</a>. I also want to check out native code from Apple, <a href="https://developer.apple.com/xcode/swiftui/">SwiftUI</a>.</p>
<p>Developing for Apple is quite costly, that you need to own a Mac (or rent online) and â‚±4450 ($99) for an individual to publish to the App Store. And it is YEARLY.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>iOS 14 App Library (is that TikTok? ðŸ˜…)</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>So, to test things out, I would be putting my app <a href="/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/">ZIP Code PH</a> on the App Store and might set a (very very small) price to support this costly Apple environment ðŸ˜‚.</p>
<h1 id="for-the-meantime">For the meantime&hellip;</h1>
<p>Go ahead and check out my apps on the <a href="ms-windows-store:publisher?name=Red David">Windows 10 Store</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=5465762079490576029">Google Play Store</a> both under Red David.</p>
<p>See you soon!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>ZIP Code PH for Android gets Dark Mode</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:17:22 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="the-pandemic-and-night-owls">The Pandemic and Night Owls</h1>
<p>My app, ZIP Code PH, has been available on Google Play Store for more than a year now and because of the pandemic, more and more people are staying at home and are mostly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night_owl_(person)">night-owls</a>.</p>
<p>And app and software developers are now giving their projects dark mode - not just to follow accessibility standards but offer an option for people to reduce or avoid eye strain.</p>
<h1 id="heres-dark-mode-for-ya">Here&rsquo;s Dark Mode for ya</h1>
<p>So here I am, picking up again on coding (for my apps) and started giving some apps a dark flavor. It almost took me a month to develop and test since available Xamarin Forms documentation didn&rsquo;t suit my liking.</p>
<h1 id="quick-app-features">Quick App Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Toggle light and dark mode</li>
<li>Quick search Philippine ZIP codes</li>
<li>Favorite (Bookmark) selected ZIP codes for easy reference</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<p>See for yourself the light and dark mode for the app below.</p>
<figure class="image">

<span style="margin: 0 10px"></span>

<figcaption><em>ZIP Code PH - Main Menu</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<figure class="image">

<span style="margin: 0 10px"></span>

<figcaption><em>ZIP Code PH - List</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>I chose <code>#222222</code> as the background color for darkmode so it is easier in the eyes (at least for me and some design posts I read somewhere). If someone requests an option for a darker color, I&rsquo;d be glad to add it. (Themes, maybe? ðŸ¤”)</p>
<h1 id="make-me-happy">Make me happy</h1>
<p>Yes, please. Make me happy by downloading the app, write a review and give a rating of 5 stars. The app is available for Android, on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.zipcodeph">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103245343">Huawei App Gallery.</a></p>
<p>It is free to download, I hope you welcome ads that earns a me a little. Thank you and until next app!</p>
<p><a href='https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.zipcodeph&pcampaignid=pcampaignidMKT-Other-global-all-co-prtnr-py-PartBadge-Mar2515-1'></a></p>
<h1 id="looking-for-a-windows-10-version">Looking for a Windows 10 version?</h1>
<p>Check out <a href="/zipcodeph-new-ui/">this old blog post</a> about the Windows 10 app.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:25:58 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>This should just be a short post to promote and showcase this Android app I developed for my job.</p>
<h1 id="am-radio-in-your-pocket">AM Radio in your Pocket</h1>
<p>Choose from RPN&rsquo;s <a href="https://rpnradio.com/" target="_blank">(Radio Philippines Network)</a> 12 regional AM stations to tune into. Just connect to the internet and be updated to the latest news, talks, and enjoy some old and new tunes.</p>
<h1 id="development">Development</h1>
<p>I tried making this app using Xamarin.Forms but the new Android implementation of the media notification sucked a** that I made the app in pure <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide">Android Java code</a>.</p>
<h1 id="app-description">App Description</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>RPN&rsquo;s 12 radio stations are situated among the three major parts of the Philippines - in Luzon, we have DZRL Batac and DZBS Baguio that will give you the latest news, updates, music and other events happening in the North in Ilocano; and DZKI Iriga to offer them in Rinkonada Bikol and/or Bikolano. Next in Visayas, DYKC Cebu and DYKB Bacolod operates in the heart of Cebu City and neighboring Bacolod City, respectively. DYKC Cebu provides an programming format that will surely make all Cebuanos and Bisaya all around the world miss home. While DYKB Bacolod gives you the most important news and talkshows in Hiligaynon and/or Ilonggo. Lastly, Mindanao holds most of our stations : DXKS Surigao, DXKO Cagayan de Oro, DXDX General Santos, DXKP Pagadian, DXXX Zamboanga, and DXKT Davao.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<figure class="image">


<figcaption><em>RPN Radio App for Android</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="download">Download</h1>
<p>The app is available to download for <strong>FREE</strong> from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031">Huawei App Store.</a></p>
<p>The app will be available soon on iOS.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>2020 Review</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/2020-review/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 13:27:12 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/2020-review/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><style>

div#gallery-2021 {
   display: flex;
    flex-wrap: wrap;
    justify-content: center;
}

div#gallery-2021 a {
  width: 30%;
  margin: 2px;
}

</style>
<p>Huh, who knew? That we can get through the sh*tty year that is 2020. ðŸ¤” And for last time (and maybe first?), let&rsquo;s take a look back to what happened with Red David&rsquo;s life in last year (SPOILER: not so much, like most of us I guess).</p>
<h1 id="january">January</h1>
<h2 id="puerto-galera-2nd-week">Puerto Galera, 2nd week</h2>
<p>New Year, New Decade! We expected a lot in 2020 coming from 2019. It started out pretty much a normal month. We would have the time to travel out of town,</p>
<p>It is always a good feeling when you can travel on the first month of the year, so that&rsquo;s what we did. So my girlfriend and I went to Puerto Galera, Mindoro and rented a place to stay for 3 days and 2 nights.</p>
<p>This place has been a must-travel not just for us both but for most of Pinoys. The white sand beach makes this place present on everybody&rsquo;s bucket list.</p>
<p>Our stay was short but it was worth-while. From walking along the beach, taking &ldquo;artistic&rdquo; photos, watch the sunset enjoyed a quite weekday evening, and chilled during the weekend evening when the &ldquo;bands&rdquo; and music will fill up the place. We also had henna tattoos, got a massage, and just tried to taste all the food.</p>
<p>Here are some of the photos we took during our short stay:</p>
<div id="gallery-2021">
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/01-21/year-in-review/i-love-puerto-galera.jpg" title="I ðŸ¤ Puerto Galera" data-thumbnail="/images/01-21/year-in-review/i-love-puerto-galera.jpg">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-breakfast.jpg" title="Toast and fried breakfast" data-thumbnail="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-breakfast.jpg">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/01-21/year-in-review/lunch-at-puerto-galera.jpg" title="Healthy lunch" data-thumbnail="/images/01-21/year-in-review/lunch-at-puerto-galera.jpg">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-no-smoking.jpg" title="No smoking beyond the point" data-thumbnail="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-no-smoking.jpg">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-sand-castle.jpg" title="Puerto Galera sand castle" data-thumbnail="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-sand-castle.jpg">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-sunset.jpg" title="Sunset at Puerto Galera" data-thumbnail="/images/01-21/year-in-review/puerto-galera-sunset.jpg">
        
    </a>
</div>
<h2 id="taal-volcano-eruption">Taal Volcano Eruption</h2>
<p>Ok hold on, this wasn&rsquo;t a part of our trip but as we are leaving the port to return to Metro Manila, we found out that Taal Volcano erupted (which was located in Batangas) but thankfully the eruption was slow that we weren&rsquo;t stranded along the way. But this news may be the start of something awful through 2020.</p>
<p>The volcano spewed a lot of volcanic ash that towns and cities, including Metro Manila.</p>
<h2 id="trip-to-bgc-last-week">Trip to BGC, last week</h2>
<p>This should be the last week of January and the KPop group Winner was doing a tour in Manila. I am not a KPop fan but my sister is that the 3 girls in our family went to SM Mall of Asia to watch them.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Baclaran Church</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<p style="font-size:0.7em;">Photo by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@ruelonguitars?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Ruel Del Jamorol</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/baclaran?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a></p>
<p>The next day, we went to visit Baclaran church to give thanks to the Lord and went straight the infamous <a href="https://megaworld-lifestylemalls.com/mall/mckinley-hill/">Venice Grand Canal Mall</a> in Taguig, a Venice-inspired open-air mall.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Venice Grand Canal Mall in Taguig</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>After exhausting the whole place, we went down to Bonifacio High Grounds which is not that far from the canal mall. We just walked around the place, took some photos, and tried to visit a museum but unfortunately they were already closed.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="february">February</h1>
<h2 id="valentines-day-and-a-new-laptop">Valentine&rsquo;s Day and a New Laptop</h2>
<p>Hmmm, nothing much happened this month, just the usual Valentine&rsquo;s date on the 14th. We just went to this semi-high end restaurant and ordered some pizza, pasta, and wine.</p>
<p>I also got a new laptop, my third Acer laptop - been an Acer user since 2011-ish because of it&rsquo;s ok specs at a lower price. I blogged about that laptop here: <a href="/new-laptop/">I Got Myself a New Laptop</a></p>
<br/>
<h1 id="march">March</h1>
<h2 id="more-like-march-ing-towards-a-global-pandemic">more like MARCH-ing Towards a Global Pandemic</h2>
<p>Oh how it started so well until a <a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019">new unknown deadly virus broke out of Wuhan, China.</a></p>
<p>It seemed the world has stopped due to lockdowns, and despite the technological advancement we have since the last decade, we still took too long for a cure.</p>
<p>These, I think, are the times we don&rsquo;t want to talk about anymore.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="april---november">April - November</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;ll sumamrize these months here, since we all have been in lock down and stayed in our homes. But luckily for us, our occupation allowed us to still make a living and let us stay in.</p>
<p>Within these months, the government has been extending and extending the quarantine every 30 days - they just fear for public panic if they announce a definite lockdown for a year.</p>
<p>I went busy during these time, did some web and app development, went on to stream some games on <a href="https://facebook.gg/RedDavidGG" target="_blank">Facebook Gaming</a> and took some online courses <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/reddvid/" target="_blank">(view my LinkedIn profile here).</a></p>
<p>With all of these, I upgraded (again) my peripherals for my convenience (sorry Girlfried, ðŸ˜‚). I bought a over-the-head headset and an earbuds, for better Zoom meetings and streaming - the JBL Quantum 200 and the HyperX Cloud earbuds. I also got myself a wireless Logitech gaming mouse, the G304, which I reviewed <a href="/g304-review/">here</a> and a Tecware mechanical keyboard TKL, which you can read more about <a href="/new-keeb/">here.</a></p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>JBL Quantum 200 (pardon the mess)</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Logitech G304</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Tecware Elite TKL</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>I also went on to upgrade my work PC&rsquo;s SSD for a better brand and higher storage, cheaper though - the XPG 8200. Also bought a JBL Go3 bluetooth speaker, and the Logitech C922 webcam, also for Zoom meetings ðŸ¤£. I blogged about the camera here: <a href="/the-logitech-c922/">Finally! Logitech C922</a></p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Logitech C922</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<br/>
<h1 id="december">December</h1>
<h2 id="christmas-and-new-years-eve">Christmas and New Year&rsquo;s Eve</h2>
<p>This might be the hardest Christmas and New Year we&rsquo;ve all faced and celebrated, but lucky enough, I had the chance to take a break from the rat race and went home to celebrate the holidays with the family together with my father whom was also stuck in his workplace city due to quarantine and lockdown.</p>
<p>The shopping continues, I got myself the Razer Hammerhead Wireless earbuds and a yellow iPhone 11 for Christmas. I did not post a blog about the wireless earbuds since the unit I got was faulty (had it replaced now). And I prefer not to flaunt my new iPhone since there&rsquo;s nothing special about it, my ultimate goal of buying one is to <a href="/developing-for-apple-soon/">develop apps for iOS.</a></p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Razer BT Earbuds and Yellow iPhone 11</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<br/>
<h1 id="hows-your-2020">How&rsquo;s Your 2020?</h1>
<p>This year had been a mix of emotions but mostly depressing. We still coping to the new normal, keeping safe, and I know we all miss socializing.</p>
<p>This might look like a tech shopping spree for me but I also grew my Facebook page from 261 to 940 this year. Played and streamed some good games - MINECRAFT!</p>
<p>Read a few books, got certificates from online courses, and especially I am still alive and healthy.</p>
<p>How did your 2020 go? Tag me on your story.
<br/>
<br/>
<br/></p>
<p><small>ðŸ“· credits: <a href="https://wsiltv.com/2021/01/01/town-says-goodbye-to-2020-with-dumpster-fire/">Dumpster Fire 2020 </a></small></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Finally! Logitech C922</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:17:51 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Yoo! I finally got the C922 PRO HD Webcam from Logitech after wishing having it for years.</p>
<p>Honestly, I bought the camera in a slightly higher price due to the model being out of stock in major stores and just got from a &ldquo;hoarder&rdquo; in Facebook marketplace. :) Harsh but true.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s get into my short blog/review/impression about this industry-standard in semi-professional streaming.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="wait">Wait</h1>
<p>You might ask, why only now? At first, I never really thought of having a good webcam as a small streamer, and I also have this app on my Android phone which makes my Nokia 7 Plus pose as a webcam. Then, I wanted the camera to be positioned well, so I bought a cheaper Logitech, the C270.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech C270 Webcam</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The C270 suited my needs - stream just now and then, and it&rsquo;s just right for video calls and conferencing. The only problem with this one is it has a bad exposure. I used the C270 for almost 3 months until I got the money to buy the beast of a camera, that is the C922.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="lets-see-922-it">Let&rsquo;s See (922) It</h1>
<p>I opened a brand new Logitech C922 way way before but it wasn&rsquo;t mine, so I already know the contents (alibi for not having pictures after unboxing ðŸ˜‚). And I also tried the unit itself so I knew the quality it brings.</p>
<p>The box contains the C922 camera, a table-top tripod, manuals and a sheet containing the free 3-month XSplit Premium codes (Again, sorry for not having pictures).</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech C922 Box</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="quick-marketing-specs">Quick (marketing) specs</h1>
<p>I won&rsquo;t dive deep into the webcam&rsquo;s specifications like weight and dimensions but here are the common &ldquo;marketing&rdquo; specs that will actually make you consider buying one:</p>
<ul>
<li>Capture 1080p @ 30fps, or</li>
<li>720p @ 60fps</li>
<li>Auto focus</li>
<li>Wide Field of View</li>
<li>Advanced camera software</li>
</ul>
<br/>
<h1 id="ha-mountable">Ha! Mountable</h1>
<p>The C922 has a screw hole for mounting onto a tripod. The tripod can be extended up to 18.5cm. Here&rsquo;s the closed tripod in three max lengths (with regards to the feet extensions).</p>
<figure class="image">




<figcaption><em>Logitech C922 Tripod Screw Hole and Lengths</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The tripod, without and with the webcam.</p>
<figure class="image">


  <figcaption><em>Logitech C922 Tripod</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The C922 also has a built-in microphone but most people, including me, advice to use an external mic instead.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="logitech-capture">Logitech Capture</h1>
<p>Upon connecting the webcam to my PC, Logitech prompted to install the companion software - Logitech Capture. The software is advanced enough for my needs - I can zoom and pan, flip the captured video horizontally and/or vertically, choose to prefer exposure or framerate, and most importantly the capture resolutions.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech Capture Software</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The software provides templates for typical sizes: FHD, 720p, and 360p; Portrait: 1080x1920, 720x1280, 360x640; and Squares: 1080x1080, 720x720, and 360x360.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech Capture Software - Resolution Options</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The software also allows you to add effects, text, etc with the Effects menu: Watermark, Text Overlay, Scene effects, Color borders, and Transitions for 2 scenes.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech Capture Software - Effects Options</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="minor-issues">Minor Issues</h1>
<p>There are a couple of issues for me, the first one really makes me annoyed is that I cannot turn off the hotkeys for the software and I have a frameless monitor which mounting the camera is a pain in the a$$ to keep it from covering up the display - even for just a centimeter.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Mounting Issue on a Frameless Monitor</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="its-great">It&rsquo;s Great!</h1>
<p>Overall, I am happy with the C922 webcam - my loved ones can see me clearly during video calls. And I thank everybody for supporting me on my <a href="https://fb.gg/RedDavidGG/" target="_blank">stream</a>, visiting my website, and checking my Windows 10 apps.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Mounting is Just Right</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>To finish this blog post, let&rsquo;s all stay safe during the pandemic - and even after the pandemic.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>New Keeb in Town</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 19:56:25 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>This is a simple review and unboxing post for my newly bought keyboard today. It is the Tecware Phantom Elite TKL with Gateron brown switches. I am using it to write this post.</p>
<p>I have used a number of mechanical keyboards in the past, the first one was an Aula one with Outemu blues. Then a TKL with blue Gateron switches, I forgot the brand, but it&rsquo;s also Chinese. And my slightly premium keyboards, the Logitech G403 and the G810.</p>
<p>The G810 was a stay-at-home keyboard for my laptop and the G403 lives in the office. And guess what, both are defective with unresponsive and ghosting keys, respectively. I thought of delaying buying a new one for &ldquo;budget&rdquo; reasons but coding with keyboard issues is a definitely a pain in the ass with constant deleting doubling keys and characters. I am looking for several &ldquo;budget&rdquo; keyboards out there, including the TNC Icarus one with Cherry MXs but the delivery time was so bad that I had to settle down with this one.</p>
<p>Coming from Logitech, I almost passed on this one for its &ldquo;gamer&rdquo; font which I don&rsquo;t think is <em>clean</em> for my desk, but my wallet said &ldquo;it&rsquo;s okay, you can live with that&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I bought one with brown switches since the old ones I had had Romer-Gs with a &ldquo;mushy-tactile&rdquo; feel on keypress so I don&rsquo;t have to worry much about them on the long run.</p>
</br>
<h1>My thoughts</h1>
<p>The box looks premium with minimal print of the logo and keyboard model on the center.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Keyboard box</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>Inside the box was the keyboard wrapped in plastic? with a keyboard cover made of plastic again, on top. It also came with 4 extra switches and a switch puller.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Inside the box</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Extra switches with puller</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>The keyboard has a TKL layout, with software-customizable RGB setting, and replaceable switches (modular). It costs php2,500, slightly costier than their Tecware Phantoms - I&rsquo;m yet to investigate why.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Tecware RGB software</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>About the &ldquo;gamer&rdquo; font I hated, this game with a cleaner font. Surprised am I! Though the printing of the keycaps has the &ldquo;stencil&rdquo; cut beneath that the LED does not shine that much. Guess I&rsquo;m okay after all. Some function keys, has this cheap white printing that I fear them to get scraped off some time soon.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>The keyboard itself</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>The RGB lighting is good with bunch of built-in modes which can be visualized and edited using their software. Here&rsquo;s what it looks like in an unlit office desk.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>RGB lighting in unlit room</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>I went ahead for a typing test and got a 76wpm results with no mistyped words. But let&rsquo;s see how long this budget badboy keyboard lasts.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all, just a short review and unboxing post for the internet people to see. If you want me to have a typing test and sound test for it, let me know.</p>
<p>Also, my apps are still available in the <a href="ms-windows-store:publisher?name=Red David" target="_blank">Microsoft Store</a> and some in the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=5465762079490576029" target="_blank">Google Play Store</a>, where I mostly get my funds for buying these stuff. You can always check them out, they&rsquo;re free to download and use, you don&rsquo;t have to buy or pay the the listed price - unless you want to.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>ZIP Code PH Gets Refreshed UI</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 22:02:34 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image2.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Over these past few months, I have been checking on some fluent design concepts and app updates over Twitter and other design sites like, Dribbble, Behance, and even Medium.
Also, I have been busy gaming and doing some reading on my spare time that I missed coding and updating some of my apps.</p>
<p>Then one time, I just found the urge to update it after seeing Michael West&rsquo;s concept layouts over Dribbble. He created a UI concept for Windows 10&rsquo;s App settings panel as seen <a href="https://dribbble.com/shots/6404804-Apps-features-Microsoft-Edge-style" target="_blank">here on his Dribbble post</a>.</p>
<p>I started coding at once, cleaning up some codes on the app beginning with the UI. And came up with the final layout.</p>
<p>Here are some screenshots of the updated app version 4.
</br></p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>version 4.0, clean and refreshed Fluent Design UI</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Favorites panel - Dark mode</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Search places - Light mode</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>You can check the <em>free</em> app here in the Microsoft Store.
</br>
<a href='//www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9nblggh5gft6?cid=storebadge&ocid=badge'></a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Your Phone Tray V2</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 21:18:31 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Your Phone Tray UWP app just got updated.</p>
<p>Version 2.0 brings few UI changes, some improvements and a breaking change.</p>
<h3 id="improvements">Improvements</h3>
<p>To improve the app, I updated the tray icon context menu to show that it should be running on Startup (see Task Manager Start up)
</p>
<p>You can also see a new menu item <strong>Enable Ctrl+Y Hotkey</strong>. If enabled, the app silently picks up the Ctrl+Y shortcut to open Your Phone app. It can be toggled if the shortcut key messes up some of your programs.</p>
<h3 id="breaking-change">Breaking change</h3>
<p>Microsoft&rsquo;s Your Phone app has been updated several times that launching it directly to the photos section shows a blank UI. For the meantime, all shortcuts to open the app will direct to messages.</p>
<p><a href="https://bit.ly/UrPhoneTray" target="_blank"><h2>You can download the app by clicking on this link</h2></a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Logitech G304 Review</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/g304-review/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 23:42:58 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/g304-review/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>So this is my short and honest review of the G304 wireless mouse.</p>
<p>As I mentioned on my previous blog post <a href="/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/">here</a>, this is my 4th mouse and my first gaming? wireless mouse. I ordered it online from DataBlitz for $39, and was delivered quickly in 2 days.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="whats-in-the-box">What&rsquo;s in the box?</h1>
<p>The box contains the wireless mouse itself, the usual manuals, Logitech Gaming promo leaflet, a blue G logo sticker, a Duracell AA battery, and a USB extension cord.</p>

<br/>
<h1 id="lets-get-physical">Let&rsquo;s get Physical!</h1>
<p>The mouse has no RGB strip like it&rsquo;s cousins (G Pro/G203) but it has a single RGB LED that indicates colored DPI assignments in Logitech G Hub. The battery compartment and the USB receiver is accessed through the lower top part of the mouse - by sliding it off the body.</p>

<p>I currently use an Energizer Lithium AA battery which I believe is lighter but I still keep the free battery whenever I need a heavier setup.</p>

<p>The power switch is located below the mouse with a red and blue color indicator for off and on state. The bottom also has an extra slide compared to the G Pro/G203.</p>

<p>The mouse shape fits perfectly in my hands and I can switch to the wired G Pro when I play some competitive games - not that this can&rsquo;t do the job. But I often stick to this, G304, every time I stream my games (shameless plug - <a href="https://fb.gg/RedDavidGG/">https://fb.gg/RedDavidGG/</a>)</p>
 

<br/>
<h1 id="reliability">Reliability</h1>
<p>I used this since day one - June 2 - and I only got a hiccup once during a Dota 2 game which made me switch to wired, and since then I used this as a daily driver and on my games. Lately, I am playing Minecraft a lot, some Dota 2, CS:GO, some Valorant, Metro Exodus, just finished Mafia II: Definitive Edition, C&amp;C Yuri&rsquo;s Revenge.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="verdict-at-last">Verdict, at last</h1>
<p>My overall experience using the same shape of a mouse will be just comfortable throughout my day - office job and being a small-time streamer. It also frees your hand positions by not limited by a wired mouse. Despite it not having an RGB, I would suggest this for small-handed people, for those who travel a lot and for gamers and streamers looking for a budget wireless gaming mouse.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="more-info">More info?</h1>
<p>Since I don&rsquo;t have a weighing scale and sea of tech reviews, you can check the thorough tech specs review from Rocket Jump Ninja <a href="https://www.rocketjumpninja.com/products/mouse/logitech-g305" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Story of my Logitech Mice</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/07-20/logi-hero.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Why do (or did) I own at least 5 of Logitech G mice despite the &ldquo;double-clicking&rdquo; issues about them? As an ECE, I knew that some percentage of any electronics produced out there do have flaws - and this is not an excuse for their price - but in the &ldquo;real&rdquo; world, these things can happen. Also, when looking at r/mechanicalkeyboards they combo their awesome keebs with a Logitech mouse despite them hating on Romer-G&rsquo;s.</p>
<p>This is my &ldquo;short&rdquo; history on my Logitech mouse shopping and usage. Here it goes:</p>
<p>If I recall correctly, my first mouse from Logitech was the G302, it has the odd shape but it just fits nicely in my hand. I used it for almost 2 years until it went &ldquo;double-clicking&rdquo; due to playing Dota 2. I just scavenged some old A4tech mouse and took out the switches (Huanos?) to replace one on the G302. The G302 still works today but it has this rattling noise due to the broken plastics inside.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Then I bought a G203, a smaller mouse sporting with the new logo. I bought this to have an RGB mouse. This is when I started to jump on the &ldquo;Logitech mouse hype&rdquo;.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Being on the &ldquo;hype train&rdquo;, I impulse bought a G403 when it became available in my country despite my current G203 still works. The G403 was not comfortable for my hand - well, the shops before don&rsquo;t have demo units - so I bought another G203 as I gave the old one to my GF for office use. The G403 is stored for now.</p>
<p></p>
<p>After some time, GF&rsquo;s workplace decided to renovate so I took the G203 back and decided to &ldquo;mod&rdquo; it and cut the wire too short making it unroutable to my home setup. This older G203 is now in my &ldquo;junk box&rdquo;.</p>
<p>I think all through the year 2019, I was looking to buy their wireless mouse - the G304. It has the same shape as the G203 and has the new HERO sensor. And that one time when I decided to finally buy one, I first asked a salesperson if there were any Logitech promos and I was told that the G Pro was 50% off. Without hesitation, I bought it instead of the G304.</p>
<p></p>
<p>The G Pro is physically the same as G203 but has a braided cable, stiffer mouse wheel, and sporting the PMW3366 optical gaming sensor. I use this in the office with a cheap mouse bungee to keep the wire neat.</p>
<p>Fast forward March 2020, city-wide was on lockdown, knowing that I would be staying in the office for quite some time, I lend my laptop to my GF for her to use. I also lend her the (working) G203.</p>
<p>After some time staying in the office, I decided to neat up my desk and I found it a hassle for wires (with dual monitors, keyboards, USB cords, and whatnot) so I thought, &ldquo;It&rsquo;s time to check that G304 I wished for the longest time. And there&rsquo;s a sale incoming too.&rdquo;</p>
<p></p>
<p>I checked Lazada but I was skeptical to buy electronics from them â€“ to avoid the hassle process of returning a defective product. This is when I learned that my &ldquo;favorite&rdquo; gaming store I bought my previous Logitech mice has a &ldquo;better&rdquo; website and I checked the G304 and it was cheaper compared to its store retail price. I bought it as a gift for myself this June.</p>
<p>Here on my desk right now is the G304 and the G Pro. I use the G304 for daily work and casual games and the G Pro for FPS and competitive gaming. I will be posting my review for the G304 soon. And sorry for the lack of better pictures of my mice.</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
