<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Fluent Design - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/fluent-design/</link>
        <description>Fluent Design - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 22:02:34 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/fluent-design/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>ZIP Code PH Gets Refreshed UI</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 22:02:34 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/zipcodeph.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Over these past few months, I have been checking on some fluent design concepts and app updates over Twitter and other design sites like, Dribbble, Behance, and even Medium.
Also, I have been busy gaming and doing some reading on my spare time that I missed coding and updating some of my apps.</p>
<p>Then one time, I just found the urge to update it after seeing Michael West&rsquo;s concept layouts over Dribbble. He created a UI concept for Windows 10&rsquo;s App settings panel as seen <a href="https://dribbble.com/shots/6404804-Apps-features-Microsoft-Edge-style" target="_blank">here on his Dribbble post</a>.</p>
<p>I started coding at once, cleaning up some codes on the app beginning with the UI. And came up with the final layout.</p>
<p>Here are some screenshots of the updated app version 4.
</br></p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>version 4.0, clean and refreshed Fluent Design UI</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Favorites panel - Dark mode</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Search places - Light mode</em></figcaption>
</figure>
</br>
<p>You can check the <em>free</em> app here in the Microsoft Store.
</br>
<a href='//www.microsoft.com/store/apps/9nblggh5gft6?cid=storebadge&ocid=badge'></a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Your Phone Tray V2</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 21:18:31 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/your-phone.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Your Phone Tray UWP app just got updated.</p>
<p>Version 2.0 brings few UI changes, some improvements and a breaking change.</p>
<h3 id="improvements">Improvements</h3>
<p>To improve the app, I updated the tray icon context menu to show that it should be running on Startup (see Task Manager Start up)
</p>
<p>You can also see a new menu item <strong>Enable Ctrl+Y Hotkey</strong>. If enabled, the app silently picks up the Ctrl+Y shortcut to open Your Phone app. It can be toggled if the shortcut key messes up some of your programs.</p>
<h3 id="breaking-change">Breaking change</h3>
<p>Microsoft&rsquo;s Your Phone app has been updated several times that launching it directly to the photos section shows a blank UI. For the meantime, all shortcuts to open the app will direct to messages.</p>
<p><a href="https://bit.ly/UrPhoneTray" target="_blank"><h2>You can download the app by clicking on this link</h2></a></p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
