<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Outliers on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/outliers/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Outliers on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 03:12:03 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/outliers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Life Updates</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/life-updates/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 03:12:03 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/life-updates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/life-updates/life-update.png" alt="Featured image of post Life Updates" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed, I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged in more than a month (since April 27th). So here are some highlights and what has happened:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;outing-before-may&#34;&gt;Outing before May&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First week I got to join an outing to a private pool to unwind. The travel is quite a pain since it was on a Friday night. It was a simple company get-together but so glad I came.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;election-season&#34;&gt;Election Season&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are yet again elect the two of the highest positions of the government and I got a week off from work (too bad they won&amp;rsquo;t let me have a laptop - so I could at least check back when needed). I got to spend my mom&amp;rsquo;s 50th birthday (again on a location with a pool) where I emcee&amp;rsquo;d for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going home also means I got to eat better and healthier. So sad I spent most inside since it was extremely hot on our place - so I got to continue reading some books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reading-books&#34;&gt;Reading Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said on a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://reddavid.me/new-in-2022/&#34; &gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, I finished Atomic Habits and finished another two books: Outliers and Essentialism. Reading this three books made me make some changes in my life especially with Essentialism which particularly affected my focus - in work, play, and life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began journaling daily activities, avoid doing &amp;ldquo;unessential&amp;rdquo; things, and take and &amp;ldquo;think&amp;rdquo; things slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reading list as of now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Subtle Art of Not Giving a F*ck&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything is F*cked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zero to One&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designing for Work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My reading is on and off to &amp;ldquo;accommodate&amp;rdquo; other things like taking short online courses on Udemy, doing some coding courses, and of course doing essential work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plans&#34;&gt;Plans?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and say I might not be posting again anytime soon (or maybe if motivation comes) since I am keeping my self busy with work, and &amp;ldquo;essential&amp;rdquo; activities. I also stopped playing video games which is sad but it also means I get to read books or code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mastering-dotnet&#34;&gt;Mastering dotnet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Took so long but I think I really get to at least master .NET and C#.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;manage-myself&#34;&gt;Manage Myself&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just think about it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tie-the-knot&#34;&gt;Tie the Knot&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting closer to October for a new chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for me, May went by so fast and it&amp;rsquo;s now June, I&amp;rsquo;m getting older in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
