<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Udemy on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/udemy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Udemy on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 01:21:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/udemy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>And... it&#39;s December</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/and...-its-december/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 01:21:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/and...-its-december/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;How many times have I apologized for not posting on my blog? 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s just recap, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-got-married&#34;&gt;I Got Married&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, people still marry despite the hardships in this f-ing country, and I am one of them last October. We both felt it is time after 8 years of being together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prior months were not all wedding-preparations as I read and took some online courses and learning programs - more about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://flutter.dev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Flutter&lt;/a&gt;, and leadership/project management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-in-depth-flutter&#34;&gt;Learning In-Depth Flutter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infamous Angela Yu’s Flutter bootcamp course on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Udemy&lt;/a&gt; has been sitting on my learning for a few months and I finally decided to take it on since I really really have to update and improve my Flutter/Dart coding - and to update some apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I faced some problems with the course since it was outdated to the current Flutter version but it all went good, thanks for the updated documentation of Flutter and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://pub.dev&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;pub.dev&lt;/a&gt; packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned DRY (&lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;on’t &lt;strong&gt;r&lt;/strong&gt;epeat &lt;strong&gt;y&lt;/strong&gt;ourself) - again - especially with Flutter’s all code UI. So, learning to convert most reusable Widgets to “components” is fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also learned a few techniques and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating-rpn-radio-app&#34;&gt;Updating RPN Radio App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my “wedding” break from the office, I came back with the motivation to update this app. Before updating, there was a “downgrade” with the app logic which disabled viewing stations’ &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;offline&lt;/em&gt; status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the app needed a UI/UX refresh - well at least for the player part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/12-22/rpnradio.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;RPN Radio App UI before and after&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;RPN Radio App UI before and after (Note: After image was taken when stations were offline)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is now available to download for free on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;gl=US&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/rpn-radio/id1571699396&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next&#34;&gt;Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also tested Flutter’s web app by building a working web version of my simple app, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ZIP Code PH&lt;/a&gt;. It’s really really simple as of this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be also going in-depth with Firebase and Firebase Auth to improve the mobile apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaming-and-streaming&#34;&gt;Gaming and Streaming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sadly, after coming back from the break, I felt no energy to play games - continue playing Assassin’s Creed: Odyssey or any other games on my Xbox PC game pass. And whenever I start a new game, I feel bored can’t motivate myself to continue playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to play Dead Space, Battlefield 4, and VALORANT this November but also felt nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is this game called 7 Days to Die on Steam that I am currently playing (not regularly, though) and I’ll see if it’s worth playing through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catch me on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/RedDavidGG&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Facebook Gaming&lt;/a&gt; when I go live, or on my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@reddavidgg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YouTube gaming channel&lt;/a&gt; for uploads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Finishing this MS Office Course on Udemy. (Or Am I?)</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/finishing-msoffice-udemy-course/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 02:21:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/finishing-msoffice-udemy-course/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/finishing-msoffice-udemy-course/udemy-og.png" alt="Featured image of post Finishing this MS Office Course on Udemy. (Or Am I?)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Udemy&lt;/a&gt; is a website catering online courses for everyone who wants to learn something new, continue learning, and to expand the current knowledge of a particular topic. And this time I wanted to advance my knowledge with Microsoft Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Udemy offers vast courses by frequently promoting sales. I actually got this complete course way back 2020 and I have been on and off the course by selecting the lecture topics to focus on. And also when I got other current shorter courses more appropriate on that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advancing-my-ms-office-knowledge&#34;&gt;Advancing my MS Office Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is entitled, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/course/microsoft-office-excel-word-access-powerpoint/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ultimate Microsoft Office; Excel, Word, PowerPoint &amp;amp; Access&lt;/a&gt; - though they added and updated it to include the 2019 and 365 updates and other Office products. I got it for around 700PHP, and I was overwhelmed with how many lectures were there for all Office products:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PowerPoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outlook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OneNote&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, there are 625 lectures with the videos totaling 68.5 hours. The topics start with an Office program explaining from the basics into advanced. And as stated on the course page, this is What I Will Learn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn the essential and advanced Microsoft Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills in Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook, Teams and Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn practical methods to backup and recover your&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Excel spreadsheets and never lose data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover the essentials of using formulas and functions in Excel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn practical methods to sort and filter your data in Excel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to insert shapes, graphics and pictures to add some &amp;ldquo;zing&amp;rdquo; to your PowerPoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wow your audience by adding animations, audio and video to PowerPoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn time saving techniques including how to copy slides, and exporting your presentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn Word tools including using columns, indents, footers, borders and watermarks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to correctly Print envelopes and labels in Word&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insert professional pictures and graphics in your Word document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sorting information and running queries in Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover how to into import data from Excel in Access&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to compact, repair and backup your Access database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to get set up in Outlook&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to customize your mailbox and view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to organize and manage your mail including ignoring, flagging and conditional formatting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to use signatures and voting buttons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with the Outlook Calendar, including creating meetings and appointments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and more!!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with Word even though it&amp;rsquo;s the most app I used and most familiar with. Then Outlook, OneNote, Excel, Teams, and now currently into PowerPoint. I actually watched the basics videos with 1.5x-1.75x speed since I already have a good understanding with it since I have been using a computer back 2006-ish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, can I finish it this April? Or do I still have to stop for the MS Access lectures (does anyone ever use Access)?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
