<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Framework on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/framework/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Framework on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:49:48 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/framework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Can .NET MAUI Make Me Switch?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/can-dotnet-maui-make-me-go-back/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:49:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/can-dotnet-maui-make-me-go-back/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/images/feat/" alt="Featured image of post Can .NET MAUI Make Me Switch?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started as a XAML/C#.NET developer for Windows apps, ranging from Windows Phone 7 and 10, and currently for Windows 10/11. But with the death of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s promise of unified development (UWP) - no more mobile platform, I thought of shifting to learn Xamarin to cover cross-platform development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Albeit the countless Xamarin developers and community for help, I faced a lot of issues everytime the framework is updated which made my workflow a hassle. And I believed that UI widgets are far basic yet complicated to control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flutter&#34;&gt;Flutter
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So more than 2 years now, I had to develop mobile apps using Flutter/Dart and I enjoyed the adjustments I have to make were to familiarize with Dart language and Flutter&amp;rsquo;s UI framework. It was also a challenge to do UI with full-code base compared to XAML designer but I felt Flutter development was quicker and more supported with various packages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microsofts-own-cross-platform-ui-framework&#34;&gt;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Own Cross-platform UI Framework
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;.NET MAUI (Multi-platform App UI) allows building apps that targets mobile, tablet, web? and desktop using C#.NET and XAML. It is progressing impressively fast with their latest Preview 14 with the help of amazing contributors in the public repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I have a short time with Xamarin.Forms,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/2022-04-05-01-04-37.png&#34;    loading=&#34;lazy&#34;  &gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an open-mind to return to my beloved C#.NET and XAML to&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
