<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Windows on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/windows/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Windows on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 14:51:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Clipchamp 1080p Exports is Now FREE</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/clipchamp-1080p-exports-is-now-free/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 14:51:56 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/clipchamp-1080p-exports-is-now-free/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/clipchamp-1080p-exports-is-now-free/clipchamp.png" alt="Featured image of post Clipchamp 1080p Exports is Now FREE" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, Microsoft acquired a web-based video editing app known as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;clipchamp.com&#34; &gt;Clipchamp&lt;/a&gt; back in Q4 2021. And after they finally put the app into Windows to become a slightly better editing tool (also on Xbox?), but all it gave to users are disappointment because of features locked behind &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.windowscentral.com/microsofts-clipchamp-video-editing-tools-are-underbaked&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;overpriced subscription&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/clipchamp-editor.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Clipchamp Editor&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Clipchamp Editor&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-exports-at-480p-give-us-1080p-please&#34;&gt;Who Exports at 480p? Give us 1080p, Please!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, who does? And surprisingly, Clichamp offers free users to ONLY export their video projects into 480p.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;display: flex;
justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Wanted to use the new Clip Champ app in Windows 11 to edit a video and now I see why they included it...it&amp;#39;s useless until you pay&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;480Peasent isn&amp;#39;t good for anything. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/MmWJWLIPS6&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/MmWJWLIPS6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Brad Sams (@bdsams) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/bdsams/status/1501925460602724354?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 10, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;good-news&#34;&gt;Good News!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a shame, but as of this writing I got an email from Clipchamp that 1080p exports is now available for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1080p exports is now the base resolution for all tiers of plans:
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;img/clipchamp-plans.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Clipchamp plans&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Clipchamp Plans&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I am yet to use this app, I&amp;rsquo;ve read online that it&amp;rsquo;s somehow intuitive by the online-based resources: templates, music &amp;amp; SFX, stock images, graphics, filters, effects, etc. that are suitable for quick and effortless video creations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the app online at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;app.clipchamp.com&#34; &gt;&lt;strong&gt;app.clipchamp.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or download from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9P1J8S7CCWWT&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Digital Spring Cleaning</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/digital-spring-cleaning/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 01:53:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/digital-spring-cleaning/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/digital-spring-cleaning/spring-cleaning.png" alt="Featured image of post Digital Spring Cleaning" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that we do not have spring season in the Philippines, it is just good to clean and/or organize (this time) our digital life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I am lazy af to clean things on a regular basis since I really suck at scheduling. This happens often when I get caught doing things that require a pretty good amount of focus (or am I just giving reasons for my laziness?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bit-of-my-digital-history&#34;&gt;Bit of My Digital History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, I started my computer life at the early age of 9/10? I just remember I was in grade 5, 1997-ish, when I fell in love with computers. But with the lack of internet, I only grew up into video games and not programming. I just picked up programming during college days when I was actually bought a laptop by my parents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tackled a bunch of languages even being an Electronics Engineering student, like C++, Turbo C, and Java. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t felt good about those languages until our thesis days where I got help with a friend, an IT student, using VB.Net. I slightly understood it better than the latter ones. It was also the start of programming in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;[http://C#.Net]%28https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/%29&#34; &gt;C#.Net&lt;/a&gt; for my Windows Phone to make apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;files&#34;&gt;Files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being into the Windows environment, files did matter and I actually had free 15GB of SkyDrive (OneDrive now) where I put my files in. While working, I actually preferred to use my laptop since it got more power than what they provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now with more than 8 years, my cloud is cluttered and having to use extensive apps, software, and services means there are alot more files scattered everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let&amp;rsquo;s go organizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organizing&#34;&gt;Organizing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-files&#34;&gt;Personal Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suck at organizing back in the day that I actually did not create folders to group similar files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I slowly group and organize files and folders properly. Starting with the Documents and Pictures folder. Although my Documents folder still sucks since Windows games create their own &lt;em&gt;saves&lt;/em&gt; folder which makes the list longer and hard to group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Pictures folder, I began grouping photos and videos based on Year &amp;gt; Month, while other non-sense images went into an Archives folder or Others folder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Personal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; folder, I grouped files by type and use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
|--Ebooks&lt;br&gt;
|--Archive&lt;br&gt;
|--Graphics&lt;br&gt;
|--Family&lt;br&gt;
|--Art&lt;br&gt;
|--Stream Assets&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the files go into further folders like inside Stream Assets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
|--Stream Assets&lt;br&gt;
&amp;emsp;|--Game Wallpapers&lt;br&gt;
&amp;emsp;|--Media&lt;br&gt;
&amp;emsp;|--Stingers&lt;br&gt;
&amp;emsp;|--Emotes&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;work-files&#34;&gt;Work Files&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems easier to organize by grouping files based on the responsibility/project, so I just went into choosing a better way to name work files. Continue reading below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;file-naming&#34;&gt;File Naming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started renaming work files since collaboration and sharing may require some context on the date and file versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;documents-docx-pdf-pptx-xlsx-etc&#34;&gt;Documents (docx, pdf, pptx, xlsx, etc)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD_TYPE_File_Name_Version#.extension&lt;br&gt;
2022-03-29_REPORT_Some_Incident_With_The_Clock.docx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;graphicsmedia-files-jpg-png-psd-mp3-mp4-etc&#34;&gt;Graphics/Media Files (jpg, png, psd, mp3, mp4 etc)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use the dash and underscore interchangeably but I am more inclined to use underscore for consistency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;file_name_tags.extension or tags_file_name.extension or both&lt;br&gt;
ad_magic_stylus_square_720x720.png &lt;br&gt; open_graph_styled_frame_template.ai&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;codes&#34;&gt;Codes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the programming language, I strictly use their naming conventions/standard for clarity and consistency. But with other types like json, txt, and other asset files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;file_name.extension&lt;br&gt;
products_list.json&lt;br&gt;
secret_codes.txt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cloud&#34;&gt;Cloud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these files now live in the cloud, OneDrive specifically, and reformatting or changing machine makes it easier to get the files again. Less hassle and worries especially when a big part of my life depends on some important files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am subscribed to Microsoft 365 Personal which offers 1TB of cloud storage and as of now I use around 48%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://onedrive.live.com?invref=fe92ac3ae0420178&amp;amp;invscr=90&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sign up to OneDrive and get 500MB additional storage space.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;share-your-way&#34;&gt;Share Your Way&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s about my file naming and folder organization and it is still on-going as of this writing. How do you organize your digital life? Share it on the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34; href=&#39;https://pngtree.com/so/cleaning&#39;&gt;cleaning png from pngtree.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My Top Apps for Windows and iPhone</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/my-top-windows-and-mobile-apps/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:45:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/my-top-windows-and-mobile-apps/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/images/og/apps.png" alt="Featured image of post My Top Apps for Windows and iPhone" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you may know by now, I am an electronics engineer but currently and mostly doing IT stuff and some casual gaming. I can also describe myself as an on-a-budget tech enthusiast - I buy top-tier pc/laptop upgrades after some time since their release or when it&amp;rsquo;s affordable enough; like when I went for 1TB Samsung 970 EVO just to hold the apps, games, and files that I leave after testing them out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I sometimes stumble upon bad or corrupted files, deleted some system files, OR EVEN installing Windows sh*ttiest Insider builds. But I seldom hold myself back reverting or reinstalling Windows to clean everything up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cloud-works&#34;&gt;The Cloud Works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trust the cloud, at least with Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s OneDrive service. I have a 1TB subscription to hold my most important files (like assets for this website, etc.) and pictures. I also always keep in hand a Windows installer on a USB stick. With all the files backed up, I simply begin reformatting it and reinstall apps and software starting with these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-apps&#34;&gt;Windows Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list may or may not be in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;avast-driver-updater&#34;&gt;Avast Driver Updater&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Windows 10, the OS also installs drivers, but I make sure they are updated using this software. It has a free trial and it works just fine. At this time, I also install graphics drivers (AMD Radeon Software or NVidia GeForce Experience).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.avast.com/en-ph/driver-updater#pc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Avast Driver Updater &amp;amp; Scanner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microsoft-office&#34;&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My subscription also contains a license to use the full desktop version of Microsoft Office, so it&amp;rsquo;s a win-win for me since this is an important skill personally and for work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/apps/CFQ7TTC0K5BF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Office 365 Personal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steam&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I don&amp;rsquo;t store my games to where my OS is installed. Steam and most game platforms allow us to locate game files, so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to redownload hundreds of GB game files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/about/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Steam&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitwarden&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I experienced being hacked, I immediately started using a password manager/generator to make my passwords not the same - YES what a shame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/download/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;winrar&#34;&gt;WinRAR&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compress and extract files and folders with unlimited 40 day trial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.win-rar.com/download.html?&amp;amp;L=0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;WinRAR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spotify&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the lack of lossless audio format, Spotify is my go-to music service. Unless it came preinstalled with Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download links: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/store/productId/9NCBCSZSJRSB&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Spotify (Microsoft Store)&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.spotify.com/kw-en/download/windows/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Spotify (.exe setup)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;voicemeeter-banana-and-virtual-cable&#34;&gt;VoiceMeeter Banana (and Virtual Cable)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most useful audio mixers software out there, donationware and flexible for my needs. It allows me to mix and manage audio inputs and outputs for other communication apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://vb-audio.com/Voicemeeter/banana.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;VoiceMeeter Banana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-studio-code&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use this as a code editor for Flutter/Dart mobile development and other source codes like this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/download&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;visual-studio&#34;&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full IDE software for various development cases. I mainly use it for Windows app development as I haven&amp;rsquo;t got into webapps as of now. I code and create apps using WinForms, WPF, and UWP (WinUI). I also tried Xamarin.Forms but I moved onto Flutter for cross-platform mobile app development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/downloads/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;obs-studio&#34;&gt;OBS Studio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used this for streaming, recording and virtual camera purposes. I now use OBS instead of XSplit. The software is FREE and much lightweight. It also has features and other free plugins made by the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://obsproject.com/download&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OBS Studio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;figma-desktop-app&#34;&gt;Figma Desktop App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This free app is browser-based but can also be downloaded as a desktop app. It was made for designers to build UI/UX interfaces - which I sometimes do when making apps. I also use this to make quick and simple logos and other graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.figma.com/downloads/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Figma Desktop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on to mobile apps. I switched to iPhone nearly a year ago because of the hardware-and-software stability (in my opinion) and the support does not end after 2 or 3 years, unlike Android. So resetting my device (after a really really bad beta software) isn&amp;rsquo;t that much of a hassle because of iCloud backups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mobile-apps&#34;&gt;Mobile Apps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my top apps that I use on a daily basis. I will not put the specific store page instead I will link to their website for mobile downloads (if available). I&amp;rsquo;ll list the apps I use on both platforms (PC and Mobile)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;spotify-1&#34;&gt;Spotify&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, we also listen to music on our phones. I can also control other playing devices&amp;rsquo; volume when AFK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitwarden-1&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app is quite simple and still got some UI bugs. Otherwise, I use this as my password manager for my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;steam-1&#34;&gt;Steam&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t often get a lot of chat from Steam but for a quicker view of what games are on sale, this app does it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microsoft-office-outlook-and-onedrive&#34;&gt;Microsoft Office, Outlook, and OneDrive&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put them together here since they are not in a suite but the new Office app user-wise deprecated the standalone Word, Excel, and PowerPoint apps since you can view and edit your documents in one app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download links: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-ww/microsoft-365/mobile&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Microsoft Office Mobile App&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/outlook-mobile-for-android-and-ios&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Outlook Mobile&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/onedrive/download&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OneDrive Mobile App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;twitter&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where I get updated to what&amp;rsquo;s happening. I only follow niche and some well-known &amp;ldquo;wholesome and awesome&amp;rdquo; Twitter users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/settings/download?lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;facebook-messenger&#34;&gt;Facebook Messenger&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yup, most family members and friends are into messenger chats so that&amp;rsquo;s no escaping Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gcash&#34;&gt;GCash&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Globe Telecom&amp;rsquo;s virtual wallet, and is now available for all networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;youtube-and-reddit&#34;&gt;YouTube and Reddit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other ways to consume online content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;microsoft-edge&#34;&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the sync being subpar to Google Chrome, I prefer this one as my main browser on my iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/edge#platform&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Microsoft Edge Web Browser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shopee&#34;&gt;Shopee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every once in a while (trust me 🤣) we just want to shop online. I recently deleted my Lazada account because it annoyed me so much with their shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Download: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://shp.ee/x6uyiut&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Shopee PH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far these are my &lt;em&gt;top&lt;/em&gt; apps that I use on my mobile phone. Let me know what&amp;rsquo;s your most used apps!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
