<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacies on Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacies on Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy for Red David Website</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/reddavid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/reddavid/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy Your privacy is important to us. It is Red David&amp;#39;s policy to respect your privacy and comply with any applicable law and regulation regarding any personal information we may collect about you, including across our website, https://reddavid.me, and other sites we own and operate. This policy is effective as of 10 March 2021 and was last updated on 10 March 2021. Information We Collect Information we collect includes both information you knowingly and actively provide us when using or participating in any of our services and promotions, and any information automatically sent by your devices in the course of accessing our products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy for ZIP Code PH for Android</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/zipcodeph-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/zipcodeph-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy
Red David built the ZIP Code PH app as an Ad Supported app. This SERVICE is provided by Red David at no cost and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.
If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy for ZIP Code PH for iOS</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/zipcodeph-for-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/zipcodeph-for-ios/</guid>
      <description>Privacy Policy
David Jessof Ballesteros (Red David) built the ZIP Code PH app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by David Jessof Ballesteros (Red David) and is intended for use as is.
This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.
If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
