<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Privacy Policies on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Privacy Policies on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Privacy Policy for Red David Website</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-website/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-website/</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your privacy is important to us. It is Red David&amp;#39;s policy to respect your privacy and comply with any applicable law and regulation regarding any personal information we may collect about you, including across our website, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://reddavid.me&#34;&gt;https://reddavid.me&lt;/a&gt;, and other sites we own and operate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 10 March 2021 and was last updated on 10 March 2021. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Information We Collect&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information we collect includes both information you knowingly and actively provide us when using or participating in any of our services and promotions, and any information automatically sent by your devices in the course of accessing our products and services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Log Data&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you visit our website, our servers may automatically log the standard data provided by your web browser. It may include your device’s Internet Protocol (IP) address, your browser type and version, the pages you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on each page, other details about your visit, and technical details that occur in conjunction with any errors you may encounter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that while this information may not be personally identifying by itself, it may be possible to combine it with other data to personally identify individual persons. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Collection and Use of Information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may collect personal information from you when you do any of the following on our website: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Use a mobile device or web browser to access our content&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Contact us via email, social media, or on any similar technologies&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;When you mention us on social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may collect, hold, use, and disclose information for the following purposes, and personal information will not be further processed in a manner that is incompatible with these purposes: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be aware that we may combine information we collect about you with general information or research data we receive from other trusted sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Security of Your Personal Information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we collect and process personal information, and while we retain this information, we will protect it within commercially acceptable means to prevent loss and theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we will do our best to protect the personal information you provide to us, we advise that no method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure, and no one can guarantee absolute data security. We will comply with laws applicable to us in respect of any data breach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are responsible for selecting any password and its overall security strength, ensuring the security of your own information within the bounds of our services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How Long We Keep Your Personal Information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We keep your personal information only for as long as we need to. This time period may depend on what we are using your information for, in accordance with this privacy policy. If your personal information is no longer required, we will delete it or make it anonymous by removing all details that identify you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if necessary, we may retain your personal information for our compliance with a legal, accounting, or reporting obligation or for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific, or historical research purposes or statistical purposes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Children’s Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not aim any of our products or services directly at children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information about children under 13. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may disclose personal information to: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;a parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of our company&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;third party service providers for the purpose of enabling them to provide their services, for example, IT service providers, data storage, hosting and server providers, advertisers, or analytics platforms&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;our employees, contractors, and/or related entities&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;our existing or potential agents or business partners&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;sponsors or promoters of any competition, sweepstakes, or promotion we run&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;courts, tribunals, regulatory authorities, and law enforcement officers, as required by law, in connection with any actual or prospective legal proceedings, or in order to establish, exercise, or defend our legal rights&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;third parties, including agents or sub-contractors, who assist us in providing information, products, services, or direct marketing to you third parties to collect and process data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;International Transfers of Personal Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The personal information we collect is stored and/or processed where we or our partners, affiliates, and third-party providers maintain facilities. Please be aware that the locations to which we store, process, or transfer your personal information may not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. If we transfer your personal information to third parties in other countries: (i) we will perform those transfers in accordance with the requirements of applicable law; and (ii) we will protect the transferred personal information in accordance with this privacy policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Your Rights and Controlling Your Personal Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You always retain the right to withhold personal information from us, with the understanding that your experience of our website may be affected. We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your rights over your personal information. If you do provide us with personal information you understand that we will collect, hold, use and disclose it in accordance with this privacy policy. You retain the right to request details of any personal information we hold about you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we receive personal information about you from a third party, we will protect it as set out in this privacy policy. If you are a third party providing personal information about somebody else, you represent and warrant that you have such person’s consent to provide the personal information to us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time. We will provide you with the ability to unsubscribe from our email-database or opt out of communications. Please be aware we may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe that any information we hold about you is inaccurate, out of date, incomplete, irrelevant, or misleading, please contact us using the details provided in this privacy policy. We will take reasonable steps to correct any information found to be inaccurate, incomplete, misleading, or out of date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you believe that we have breached a relevant data protection law and wish to make a complaint, please contact us using the details below and provide us with full details of the alleged breach. We will promptly investigate your complaint and respond to you, in writing, setting out the outcome of our investigation and the steps we will take to deal with your complaint. You also have the right to contact a regulatory body or data protection authority in relation to your complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Limits of Our Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our website may link to external sites that are not operated by us. Please be aware that we have no control over the content and policies of those sites, and cannot accept responsibility or liability for their respective privacy practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Changes to This Policy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At our discretion, we may change our privacy policy to reflect updates to our business processes, current acceptable practices, or legislative or regulatory changes. If we decide to change this privacy policy, we will post the changes here at the same link by which you are accessing this privacy policy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If required by law, we will get your permission or give you the opportunity to opt in to or opt out of, as applicable, any new uses of your personal information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any questions or concerns regarding your privacy, you may contact us using the following details: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto://reddavidapps@outlook.com&#34; &gt;reddavidapps@outlook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Privacy Policy for ZIP Code PH for Android</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-android-apps/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-android-apps/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red David built the ZIP Code PH app as an Ad Supported app. This SERVICE is provided by Red David at no cost and is intended for use as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at ZIP Code PH unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Collection and Use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app does use third party services that may collect information used to identify you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to privacy policy of third party service providers used by the app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Play Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://support.google.com/admob/answer/6128543?hl=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AdMob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device&amp;rsquo;s internal memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Providers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To facilitate our Service;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide the Service on our behalf;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To perform Service-related services; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links to Other Sites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children’s Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Services do not address anyone under the age of 13. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. In the case I discover that a child under 13 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes to This Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 2021-03-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto://reddavidapps@outlook.com&#34; &gt;reddavidapps@outlook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;This privacy policy page was created at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://privacypolicytemplate.net&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;privacypolicytemplate.net&lt;/a&gt; and modified/generated by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;App Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Privacy Policy for ZIP Code PH for iOS</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-ios-apps/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-ios-apps/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Jessof Ballesteros (Red David) built the ZIP Code PH app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by David Jessof Ballesteros (Red David) and is intended for use as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at ZIP Code PH unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Collection and Use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device&amp;rsquo;s internal memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Providers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To facilitate our Service;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide the Service on our behalf;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To perform Service-related services; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links to Other Sites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children’s Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Services do not address anyone under the age of 13. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. In the case I discover that a child under 13 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes to This Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 2021-03-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto://reddavidapps@outlook.com&#34; &gt;reddavidapps@outlook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;This privacy policy page was created at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://privacypolicytemplate.net&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;privacypolicytemplate.net&lt;/a&gt; and modified/generated by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;App Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
