<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Privacy Policies on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Privacy Policies on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Privacy Policy</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: The opinions expressed in this website are my own personal opinions and in no way represent my employer&amp;rsquo;s view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last updated: August 3, 2023&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog &amp;amp; Site (&amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;) operates the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.reddavid.me&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.reddavid.me&lt;/a&gt; website (the &amp;ldquo;Service&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.reddavid.me/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.reddavid.me/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;definitions&#34;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Service is the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.reddavid.me/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.reddavid.me/&lt;/a&gt; website operated by David Ballesteros, an Individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Data&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Personal data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usage Data&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your device (computer or mobile device).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Controller&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner which any personal information are, or are to be, processed.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Processors (or Service Providers)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Subject (or User)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-collection-and-use&#34;&gt;Information Collection and Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TYPES OF DATA COLLECTED&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (&amp;ldquo;Personal Data&amp;rdquo;). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email address&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First name and last name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookies and Usage Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usage Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used (&amp;ldquo;Usage Data&amp;rdquo;). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer&amp;rsquo;s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tracking &amp;amp; Cookies Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example of Cookies we use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Session Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;. We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preference Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advertising Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;. Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;use-of-data&#34;&gt;Use of Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog uses the collected data for various purposes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide and maintain our Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To notify you about changes to our Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide customer support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To monitor the usage of our Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To detect, prevent and address technical issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;legal-basis-for-processing-personal-data-under-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr&#34;&gt;Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog may process your Personal Data because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to perform a contract with you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have given us permission to do so&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The processing is in our legitimate interests and it&amp;rsquo;s not overridden by your rights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To comply with the law&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;retention-of-data&#34;&gt;Retention of Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transfer-of-data&#34;&gt;Transfer of Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to - and maintained on - computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclosure-of-data&#34;&gt;Disclosure of Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEGAL REQUIREMENTS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To comply with a legal obligation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To protect and defend the rights or property of David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To protect against legal liability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;security-of-data&#34;&gt;Security of Data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;do-not-track-signals&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Not Track&amp;rdquo; Signals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not support Do Not Track (&amp;ldquo;DNT&amp;rdquo;). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;your-data-protection-rights-under-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr&#34;&gt;Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you. Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right of rectification. You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to object. You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right of restriction. You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to data portability. You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The right to withdraw consent. You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where David Ballesteros&amp;rsquo;s Blog relied on your consent to process your personal information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;service-providers&#34;&gt;Service Providers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (&amp;ldquo;Service Providers&amp;rdquo;), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANALYTICS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy &amp;amp; Terms web page: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://policies.google.com/privacy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://policies.google.com/privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADVERTISING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google AdSense &amp;amp; DoubleClick Cookie&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google&amp;rsquo;s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;links-to-other-sites&#34;&gt;Links to Other Sites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party&amp;rsquo;s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;childrens-privacy&#34;&gt;Children&amp;rsquo;s Privacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (&amp;ldquo;Children&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guarian and you are aware that your child has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;changes-to-this-privacy-policy&#34;&gt;Changes to This Privacy Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the &amp;ldquo;effective data&amp;rdquo; at the top of this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-us&#34;&gt;Contact Us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By email: hi at reddavid dot me&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Privacy Policy for ZIP Code PH for Android</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-android-apps/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-android-apps/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red David built the ZIP Code PH app as an Ad Supported app. This SERVICE is provided by Red David at no cost and is intended for use as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at ZIP Code PH unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Collection and Use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The app does use third party services that may collect information used to identify you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link to privacy policy of third party service providers used by the app&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Play Services&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://support.google.com/admob/answer/6128543?hl=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AdMob&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device&amp;rsquo;s internal memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Providers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To facilitate our Service;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide the Service on our behalf;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To perform Service-related services; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links to Other Sites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children’s Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Services do not address anyone under the age of 13. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. In the case I discover that a child under 13 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes to This Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 2021-03-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto://reddavidapps@outlook.com&#34; &gt;reddavidapps@outlook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;This privacy policy page was created at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://privacypolicytemplate.net&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;privacypolicytemplate.net&lt;/a&gt; and modified/generated by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;App Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Privacy Policy for ZIP Code PH for iOS</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-ios-apps/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 13:10:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/privacy/privacy-policy-ios-apps/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Jessof Ballesteros (Red David) built the ZIP Code PH app as a Commercial app. This SERVICE is provided by David Jessof Ballesteros (Red David) and is intended for use as is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is used to inform visitors regarding my policies with the collection, use, and disclosure of Personal Information if anyone decided to use my Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you choose to use my Service, then you agree to the collection and use of information in relation to this policy. The Personal Information that I collect is used for providing and improving the Service. I will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, which is accessible at ZIP Code PH unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Collection and Use&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a better experience, while using our Service, I may require you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information. The information that I request will be retained on your device and is not collected by me in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform you that whenever you use my Service, in a case of an error in the app I collect data and information (through third party products) on your phone called Log Data. This Log Data may include information such as your device Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, device name, operating system version, the configuration of the app when utilizing my Service, the time and date of your use of the Service, and other statistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cookies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cookies are files with a small amount of data that are commonly used as anonymous unique identifiers. These are sent to your browser from the websites that you visit and are stored on your device&amp;rsquo;s internal memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service does not use these “cookies” explicitly. However, the app may use third party code and libraries that use “cookies” to collect information and improve their services. You have the option to either accept or refuse these cookies and know when a cookie is being sent to your device. If you choose to refuse our cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of this Service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service Providers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may employ third-party companies and individuals due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To facilitate our Service;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide the Service on our behalf;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To perform Service-related services; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to inform users of this Service that these third parties have access to your Personal Information. The reason is to perform the tasks assigned to them on our behalf. However, they are obligated not to disclose or use the information for any other purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I value your trust in providing us your Personal Information, thus we are striving to use commercially acceptable means of protecting it. But remember that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and reliable, and I cannot guarantee its absolute security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links to Other Sites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Service may contain links to other sites. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that site. Note that these external sites are not operated by me. Therefore, I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of these websites. I have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third-party sites or services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Children’s Privacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Services do not address anyone under the age of 13. I do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. In the case I discover that a child under 13 has provided me with personal information, I immediately delete this from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your child has provided us with personal information, please contact me so that I will be able to do necessary actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Changes to This Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. Thus, you are advised to review this page periodically for any changes. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This policy is effective as of 2021-03-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or suggestions about my Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact me at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto://reddavidapps@outlook.com&#34; &gt;reddavidapps@outlook.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;This privacy policy page was created at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://privacypolicytemplate.net&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;privacypolicytemplate.net&lt;/a&gt; and modified/generated by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app-privacy-policy-generator.nisrulz.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;App Privacy Policy Generator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
