<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mechanical Keyboard on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/mechanical-keyboard/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Mechanical Keyboard on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 19:56:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/mechanical-keyboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>New Keeb in Town</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 19:56:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/images/feat/tecware.jpg" alt="Featured image of post New Keeb in Town" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;foreword&#34;&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple review and unboxing post for my newly bought keyboard today. It is the Tecware Phantom Elite TKL with Gateron brown switches. I am using it to write this post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have used a number of mechanical keyboards in the past, the first one was an Aula one with Outemu blues. Then a TKL with blue Gateron switches, I forgot the brand, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Chinese. And my slightly premium keyboards, the Logitech G403 and the G810.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The G810 was a stay-at-home keyboard for my laptop and the G403 lives in the office. And guess what, both are defective with unresponsive and ghosting keys, respectively. I thought of delaying buying a new one for &amp;ldquo;budget&amp;rdquo; reasons but coding with keyboard issues is a definitely a pain in the ass with constant deleting doubling keys and characters. I am looking for several &amp;ldquo;budget&amp;rdquo; keyboards out there, including the TNC Icarus one with Cherry MXs but the delivery time was so bad that I had to settle down with this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from Logitech, I almost passed on this one for its &amp;ldquo;gamer&amp;rdquo; font which I don&amp;rsquo;t think is &lt;em&gt;clean&lt;/em&gt; for my desk, but my wallet said &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s okay, you can live with that&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought one with brown switches since the old ones I had had Romer-Gs with a &amp;ldquo;mushy-tactile&amp;rdquo; feel on keypress so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry much about them on the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;unboxing&#34;&gt;Unboxing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The box looks premium with minimal print of the logo and keyboard model on the center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/08-20/new-kb/box.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Tecware Phantom TKL box&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Tecware Phantom TKL box&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the box was the keyboard wrapped in plastic. It also came with 4 extra switches and a switch puller.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/08-20/new-kb/inside.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Tecware Phantom unbox&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Tecware Phantom unbox&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/08-20/new-kb/free-switches-puller.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Extra switches and puller&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Extra switches with puller&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tkl&#34;&gt;TKL&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard has a TKL layout, with software-customizable RGB setting, and replaceable switches (modular). It costs php2,500, slightly costier than their Tecware Phantoms - I&amp;rsquo;m yet to investigate why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/08-20/new-kb/tecware-rgb-software.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Tecware software for RGB modes&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Tecware RGB software&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About the &amp;ldquo;gamer&amp;rdquo; font I hated, this game with a cleaner font. Surprised am I! Though the printing of the keycaps has the &amp;ldquo;stencil&amp;rdquo; cut beneath that the LED does not shine that much. Guess I&amp;rsquo;m okay after all. Some function keys, has this cheap white printing that I fear them to get scraped off some time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/08-20/new-kb/keyboard.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Tecware Phantom Elite&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The keyboard itself&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rgb&#34;&gt;RGB&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RGB lighting is good with bunch of built-in modes which can be visualized and edited using their software. Here&amp;rsquo;s what it looks like in an unlit office desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/08-20/new-kb/rgb.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Box contents&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;RGB lighting in unlit room&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went ahead for a typing test and got a 76wpm results with no mistyped words. But let&amp;rsquo;s see how long this budget badboy keyboard lasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all, just a short review and unboxing post for the internet people to see. If you want me to have a typing test and sound test for it, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;support-me&#34;&gt;Support Me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, my apps are still available in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;ms-windows-store:publisher?name=Red David&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Microsoft Store&lt;/a&gt; and some in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=5465762079490576029&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt;, where I mostly get my funds for buying these stuff. You can always check them out, they&amp;rsquo;re free to download and use, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to buy or pay the the listed price - unless you want to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
