<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup on Red David Blog</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/setup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Setup on Red David Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:17:51 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/setup/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finally! Logitech C922</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:17:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</guid>
      <description>Yoo! I finally got the C922 PRO HD Webcam from Logitech after wishing having it for years.
Honestly, I bought the camera in a slightly higher price due to the model being out of stock in major stores and just got from a &amp;ldquo;hoarder&amp;rdquo; in Facebook marketplace. :) Harsh but true.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get into my short blog/review/impression about this industry-standard in semi-professional streaming.
Wait You might ask, why only now?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Keeb in Town</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 19:56:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-keeb/</guid>
      <description>This is a simple review and unboxing post for my newly bought keyboard today. It is the Tecware Phantom Elite TKL with Gateron brown switches. I am using it to write this post.
I have used a number of mechanical keyboards in the past, the first one was an Aula one with Outemu blues. Then a TKL with blue Gateron switches, I forgot the brand, but it&amp;rsquo;s also Chinese. And my slightly premium keyboards, the Logitech G403 and the G810.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logitech G304 Review</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/g304-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 23:42:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/g304-review/</guid>
      <description>So this is my short and honest review of the G304 wireless mouse.
As I mentioned on my previous blog post here, this is my 4th mouse and my first gaming? wireless mouse. I ordered it online from DataBlitz for $39, and was delivered quickly in 2 days.
What&amp;rsquo;s in the box? The box contains the wireless mouse itself, the usual manuals, Logitech Gaming promo leaflet, a blue G logo sticker, a Duracell AA battery, and a USB extension cord.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story of my Logitech Mice</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/story-of-owning-logitech-mice/</guid>
      <description>Why do (or did) I own at least 5 of Logitech G mice despite the &amp;ldquo;double-clicking&amp;rdquo; issues about them? As an ECE, I knew that some percentage of any electronics produced out there do have flaws - and this is not an excuse for their price - but in the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; world, these things can happen. Also, when looking at r/mechanicalkeyboards they combo their awesome keebs with a Logitech mouse despite them hating on Romer-G&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
