<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>C922 - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/c922/</link>
        <description>C922 - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:17:51 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/c922/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Finally! Logitech C922</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:17:51 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/the-logitech-c922/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/logitech-c922.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Yoo! I finally got the C922 PRO HD Webcam from Logitech after wishing having it for years.</p>
<p>Honestly, I bought the camera in a slightly higher price due to the model being out of stock in major stores and just got from a &ldquo;hoarder&rdquo; in Facebook marketplace. :) Harsh but true.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s get into my short blog/review/impression about this industry-standard in semi-professional streaming.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="wait">Wait</h1>
<p>You might ask, why only now? At first, I never really thought of having a good webcam as a small streamer, and I also have this app on my Android phone which makes my Nokia 7 Plus pose as a webcam. Then, I wanted the camera to be positioned well, so I bought a cheaper Logitech, the C270.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech C270 Webcam</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The C270 suited my needs - stream just now and then, and it&rsquo;s just right for video calls and conferencing. The only problem with this one is it has a bad exposure. I used the C270 for almost 3 months until I got the money to buy the beast of a camera, that is the C922.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="lets-see-922-it">Let&rsquo;s See (922) It</h1>
<p>I opened a brand new Logitech C922 way way before but it wasn&rsquo;t mine, so I already know the contents (alibi for not having pictures after unboxing 😂). And I also tried the unit itself so I knew the quality it brings.</p>
<p>The box contains the C922 camera, a table-top tripod, manuals and a sheet containing the free 3-month XSplit Premium codes (Again, sorry for not having pictures).</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech C922 Box</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="quick-marketing-specs">Quick (marketing) specs</h1>
<p>I won&rsquo;t dive deep into the webcam&rsquo;s specifications like weight and dimensions but here are the common &ldquo;marketing&rdquo; specs that will actually make you consider buying one:</p>
<ul>
<li>Capture 1080p @ 30fps, or</li>
<li>720p @ 60fps</li>
<li>Auto focus</li>
<li>Wide Field of View</li>
<li>Advanced camera software</li>
</ul>
<br/>
<h1 id="ha-mountable">Ha! Mountable</h1>
<p>The C922 has a screw hole for mounting onto a tripod. The tripod can be extended up to 18.5cm. Here&rsquo;s the closed tripod in three max lengths (with regards to the feet extensions).</p>
<figure class="image">




<figcaption><em>Logitech C922 Tripod Screw Hole and Lengths</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The tripod, without and with the webcam.</p>
<figure class="image">


  <figcaption><em>Logitech C922 Tripod</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The C922 also has a built-in microphone but most people, including me, advice to use an external mic instead.</p>
<br/>
<h1 id="logitech-capture">Logitech Capture</h1>
<p>Upon connecting the webcam to my PC, Logitech prompted to install the companion software - Logitech Capture. The software is advanced enough for my needs - I can zoom and pan, flip the captured video horizontally and/or vertically, choose to prefer exposure or framerate, and most importantly the capture resolutions.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech Capture Software</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The software provides templates for typical sizes: FHD, 720p, and 360p; Portrait: 1080x1920, 720x1280, 360x640; and Squares: 1080x1080, 720x720, and 360x360.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech Capture Software - Resolution Options</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>The software also allows you to add effects, text, etc with the Effects menu: Watermark, Text Overlay, Scene effects, Color borders, and Transitions for 2 scenes.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Logitech Capture Software - Effects Options</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="minor-issues">Minor Issues</h1>
<p>There are a couple of issues for me, the first one really makes me annoyed is that I cannot turn off the hotkeys for the software and I have a frameless monitor which mounting the camera is a pain in the a$$ to keep it from covering up the display - even for just a centimeter.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Mounting Issue on a Frameless Monitor</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="its-great">It&rsquo;s Great!</h1>
<p>Overall, I am happy with the C922 webcam - my loved ones can see me clearly during video calls. And I thank everybody for supporting me on my <a href="https://fb.gg/RedDavidGG/" target="_blank">stream</a>, visiting my website, and checking my Windows 10 apps.</p>
<figure class="image">

  <figcaption><em>Mounting is Just Right</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>To finish this blog post, let&rsquo;s all stay safe during the pandemic - and even after the pandemic.</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
