<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Red David Blog</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Red David Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:17:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/android/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZIP Code PH for Android gets Dark Mode</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:17:22 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</guid>
      <description>The Pandemic and Night Owls My app, ZIP Code PH, has been available on Google Play Store for more than a year now and because of the pandemic, more and more people are staying at home and are mostly night-owls.
And app and software developers are now giving their projects dark mode - not just to follow accessibility standards but offer an option for people to reduce or avoid eye strain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android</title>
      <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:25:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</guid>
      <description>This should just be a short post to promote and showcase this Android app I developed for my job.
AM Radio in your Pocket Choose from RPN&amp;rsquo;s (Radio Philippines Network) 12 regional AM stations to tune into. Just connect to the internet and be updated to the latest news, talks, and enjoy some old and new tunes.
Development I tried making this app using Xamarin.Forms but the new Android implementation of the media notification sucked a** that I made the app in pure Android Java code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
