<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Android - Tag - Red David | Tech, Gaming, and Coding Blog</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/android/</link>
        <description>Android - Tag - Red David | Tech, Gaming, and Coding Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 03:22:25 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/android/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>(Updated) RPN News Mobile App Released</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpn-news-released/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 03:22:25 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpn-news-released/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpn-news.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="update">Update</h1>
<p>The app is now available for iPhones. See the <a href="#download-here">download section</a> below.</p>
<hr >
<p>It&rsquo;s been a while again since my last post but there were no significant updates lately - besides another week-long vacation. So let me introduce this new mobile app from RPN that I developed and releasing now.</p>
<h1 id="delays">Delays</h1>
<p>The app had a working beta for Android devices for awhile now with bare experience and a better update has been in the works. I took the time to work out the database functions, UI and UX, and some other features (mobile ads, and customized links).</p>
<p>I apologize for the delay but I just made sure these features are working for production.</p>
<h1 id="app-details">App Details</h1>
<p>Most brands nowadays accompany their line of business with a mobile app, beside the <a href="https://tunein.rpnradio.com/download" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN Radio app</a> which was released so much earlier, I am now finally be able to bring news mobile app for Android devices, and iPhones.</p>
<p>Right now, the app is a feed for the provincial news as visible on <a href="https://rpnradio.com/category/provincial-news/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN website</a>. The news are gathered by our provincial/regional news stations that you can read from the website or from the app - for much easier reading and sharing.</p>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<p>It took too long to release the app that the version is now at 2.1. Below are screenshots (store previews for iPhone and Android).</p>
<style>

div#gallery-rpn-news {
   display: flex;
    flex-wrap: wrap;
    justify-content: center;
}

div#gallery-rpn-news a {
  width: 20%;
  margin: 2px;
}

</style>
<div id="gallery-rpn-news">
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-1.png" title="News feed (iPhone)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-1.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-2.png" title="News details (iPhone)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-2.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-3.png" title="About page (iPhone)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpn-news-apple-3.png">
        
    </a>
</div>
<div id="gallery-rpn-news">
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-1.png" title="News feed (Android)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-1.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-2.png" title="News details (Android)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-2.png">
        
    </a>
<a class="lightgallery" href="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-3.png" title="About page (Android)" data-thumbnail="/images/12-21/rpn-news/rpnnews-store-3.png">
        
    </a>
</div>
<h1 id="download-here">Download Here</h1>
<p>The app is available now on the Google Play Store: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.news&amp;hl=en&amp;gl=US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN News - Apps on Google Play</a></p>
<p>Update: Download for iPhone here: <a href="ttps://apps.apple.com/app/id1590143546" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RPN News on the App Store</a></p>
<p>As for Huawei devices (App Gallery) <del>and iPhone App Store</del>, the app is still under review for each platform. Will add the links as soon as they&rsquo;re approved.</p>
<h1 id="whats-next">What&rsquo;s Next</h1>
<p>Here are the milestones I am looking forward to bring:</p>
<h3 id="milestone-22">Milestone 2.2+</h3>
<ul>
<li>News Filter (by Station or tags)</li>
<li>Search</li>
<li>National and International news (courtesy of BusinessMirror news)</li>
<li>Customizable fonts</li>
<li>Read aloud</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="milestone-30">Milestone 3.0</h3>
<ul>
<li>Integrate stations' live videos (YouTube)</li>
<li>Integrate stations' VODs (video-on-demand)</li>
</ul>
<p>As always, you can follow me on <a href="https://twitter.com/reddvid" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Twitter</a> for mini updates.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>#TI10 and Appdates</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/ti-and-appdates/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 03:53:07 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/ti-and-appdates/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/og/ti10-appdates.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Let&rsquo;s start with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_International_2021#:~:text=The%20International%202021%2C%20also%20known,2%20world%20championship%20esports%20tournament." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The International</a>, shortened as TI, Valve&rsquo;s yearly Dota 2 tournament where the 18 of the best teams around the world gather to fight for the Aegis of the Champions every year. After being canceled and waiting for more than 2 years it is now happening, without an audience in Bucharest, Romania with a total prizepool of $40M+.</p>
<center>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">The International 10 Prize Pool Breakdown. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TI10?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TI10</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Dota2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Dota2</a> <a href="https://t.co/76mHH1MZue">pic.twitter.com/76mHH1MZue</a></p>&mdash; Wykrhm Reddy (@wykrhm) <a href="https://twitter.com/wykrhm/status/1444037357775179779?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 1, 2021</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

</center>
<p>I only play the game against custom BOT scripts 🤣 just to past time or just to be updated with what patches <a href="https://dota2.fandom.com/wiki/IceFrog" target="_blank">IceFrog</a> brings to the game. What I mostly do is watch major tournaments especially those when teams need to earn <a href="https://liquipedia.net/dota2/Dota_Pro_Circuit" target="_blank">DPC points</a> for entering the prestigious TI.</p>
<h2 id="10-days-of-dota">10 Days of DOTA</h2>
<p>#TI10 started on October 7th with 18 qualified teams playing playoffs on the group stage to determine their position either on the upper or lower bracket; and where two teams: Thunder Predator and SG, in the end, bid farewell for the Main Stage and championship.</p>
<center>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">TI10 Groups Final Standings. <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TI10?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TI10</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Dota2?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Dota2</a> <a href="https://t.co/JBXC9z7hBc">pic.twitter.com/JBXC9z7hBc</a></p>&mdash; Wykrhm Reddy (@wykrhm) <a href="https://twitter.com/wykrhm/status/1447199723308269568?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2021</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

</center>
<p>Now, as of this writing, we just ended Day 3 of the Main Stage and I&rsquo;ve followed and watched most of the games. Fnatic, a SEA team with 2 Pinoy players, got eliminated on Day 2 just after getting past a heart-wrenching Best-of-One&rsquo;s on the Lower Bracket the day before. The last SEA representative, T1, would have to give their best on their lower bracket run.</p>
<p>{{ &lt; figure src=&ldquo;<a href="https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FBrySN5VIAAtGqh?format=jpg&amp;name=large%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://pbs.twimg.com/media/FBrySN5VIAAtGqh?format=jpg&name=large"</a> &gt; }}</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="https://twitter.com/wykrhm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wykrhm Reddy (@wykrhm)</a> for being such a good Dota Community Man.</p>
<h2 id="sekretong-malupet">Sekretong Malupet</h2>
<p>Watching all games and supporting SEA teams, my heart still goes to Team Secret for all their TI runs. Right now, they already secured Top 3 finish for the semifinals game against PSG.LGD.</p>
<center>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">We made a promise. We delivered.<br><br>UPPER BRACKET: SECURED 🖤<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/SecretDota?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#SecretDota</a> <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/TI10?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#TI10</a> <a href="https://t.co/4V6czHXzhI">pic.twitter.com/4V6czHXzhI</a></p>&mdash; Team Secret (@teamsecret) <a href="https://twitter.com/teamsecret/status/1447192871677857796?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 10, 2021</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

</center>
<p>I follow the games by watching <a href="https://www.twitch.tv/singsing" target="_blank">singsing&rsquo;s Twitch stream</a> as he and his (pepega) friends cast and analyze the stream - chill and fun. This way I can watch (or listen) while doing app coding.</p>
<h2 id="coding-and-appdates">Coding and Appdates</h2>
<p>This 10-day tournament meant a break from me streaming (to catch the games) which then allowed me time to code for RPN News mobile app.</p>
<p>My job (finally) provided me a Samsung A71 Android phone to test the app (and for work-related stuff) after my old personal phone went bust; though I still use my iPhone 11 to test the iOS code - maybe soon? 🤣</p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <p>Samsung A71</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The app has been up on the Google Play Store for some time (as I blogged <a href="https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/" target="_blank">here</a>) and lacked significant updates. It stayed that way for a while until all busy-ness and code-confusion (is this even a term?) has subsided.</p>
<p>These past days, I managed to release an update for the Android beta app and also started a TestFlight for iOS devices.</p>
<p>I decided to version the app as 2.0 as this was a complete rework from the old code despite not publicly releasing a version 1.0. The app was previously coded on C#/Xamarin Forms but the documentation and support I needed was &ldquo;not there&rdquo;, then I started to code on Dart/Flutter for RPN Radio which made things easier - being a single-codebase mobile app development.</p>
<p>Version 2.0 brings a new UI and supports offline mode - see downloaded news (as opposed to before that it will not work when there is no internet; though it is always recommended to be connected to get the latest news).</p>
<figure><figcaption>
            <p>News Items</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure><figcaption>
            <p>News Details Page</p>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h3 id="get-into-the-beta-test">Get into the Beta Test</h3>
<p>The app is available for testing and I welcome your feedback after getting the app here from <strong><a href="https://bit.ly/2YVpJC9" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Google Play Store</a></strong> and <a href="https://apple.co/2XaMBNl" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Apple TestFlight</a>.</p>
<p>Or scan the QR code below:</p>
<h4 id="google-play-store">Google Play Store</h4>
<figure>
</figure>

<h4 id="apple-testflight">Apple TestFlight</h4>
<figure>
</figure>

<p>You may submit your feedback using built-in tools from Google or TestFlight, sending an <a href="mailto:info@rpnradio.com" rel="">email</a>, or any on my socials.</p>
<p>I will try my best to get the app working for a public release.</p>
<hr>
<p>That&rsquo;s it for now folks, <strong>let&rsquo;s watch and enjoy some Dota</strong>.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Flutter Coding</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/flutter-coding/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 22:06:53 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/flutter-coding/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/android-love-flutter.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>I&rsquo;ve heard about Flutter a long time ago but never actually used it or read in-depth about it. But I knew it was a UI framework from Google which uses a single code-base for mobile and web apps.</p>
<p>As you may know now, I developed some apps for Android and iOS using their native languages - Java and SwiftUI - and not a single-codebase language like Flutter. But I did try to code the RPN Radio app using Xamarin.Forms but the implementation of the Audio Players s*cks a$$ to be honest.</p>
<p>Coding with their native languages was just a personal challenge for me being tech-savvy and wanted to experiment and dive myself to their &ldquo;native world&rdquo;.</p>
<h1 id="android-and-bad-java-code">Android and Bad (Java) Code</h1>
<p>The Android Java code stuff was working - well, not that well - the implementation of the player was frequently bugged that it causes the app to crash. I tried several work arounds to the code to prevent the nasties, until I realized this is bad code.</p>
<p>To satisfy myself, and the users, I challenged myself to rebuild the app using Flutter.</p>
<p>Ever since March started, I started reading about Flutter and did some basic UI.</p>
<p>But first, let me tell you how I installed Flutter on Windows.</p>
<h1 id="pre-installation-pre-requisites">Pre-installation (Pre-requisites?)</h1>
<ul>
<li>Make sure you have Git on your device. I installed Git for Windows</li>
<li>I&rsquo;ve had Android Studio installed on my system ever since I coded for Android, which is also a recommended IDE for Flutter.</li>
<li>Some Android SDKs and;</li>
<li>Google Chrome browser.</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="installation">Installation</h1>
<p>I pretty much followed the recommended guide as stated here: <a href="https://flutter.dev/docs/get-started/install/windows" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Install Flutter (Windows)</a>. But instead of <code>C:\src\flutter</code>, I put it a level higher like this: <code>C:\flutter</code>.</p>
<p>Then added environment variable to Path. &lt;- This part is important if you want to run flutter commands in the command line</p>
<p>Ran <code>flutter doctor</code> until all requirements are check out</p>
<h1 id="ide-wait">IDE, wait&hellip;</h1>
<p>My IDE of choice is Android Studio, so I can use the emulators I already created and to avoid any additional setup when choosing another.</p>
<p>Upon opening the IDE, it was said that creating a new Flutter project should be there on the menu screen but it was missing!</p>
<p>Even though <code>flutter doctor</code> checked everything, I was disappointed that I can&rsquo;t start right away. Scraping the internet for solutions, I checked Android Studio&rsquo;s configuration and there, I downloaded some Flutter and Dart plugins which after a software restart, I can now create a new Flutter project.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>New Flutter Project</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>Since, the app I am planning to rebuild in Flutter is single-paged, it is a good starting-point to play around the Flutter widgets.</p>
<p>Coming from XAML, where everything seems &ldquo;as is&rdquo;, I am so uncomfortable about coding UI using script-like codes. But having started SwiftUI for a few weeks, I pretty much can stand it. 😅</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Flutter UI Code</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="beginning">Beginning</h1>
<p>Being the beginner, again, I am on my way to building to much more with Flutter with prettier code and nicer implementations.</p>
<p>I am now reading some books and watching some tutorials on YouTube to help me advance a little more each day.</p>
<p>Ever since February began, I have been active to coding again. Learning new stuff that I do enjoy!</p>
<p>Thanks for reading my blog post, and will share some updates on how I would use Flutter sometime soon! Always take care peeps!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Tune In RPN Radio Update</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/tunein-update/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 20:30:09 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/tunein-update/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpn-tunein.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>I updated the tune-in website for RPN. This post will detail the changes, what&rsquo;s new or removed, and how the update went.</p>
<h1 id="mainpage-and-mobile-first-design">MainPage and Mobile-First Design</h1>
<p>The main page remains got a few changes, starting with the font face and size. Before the update, the font family forced to check for <a href="https://www.marksimonson.com/fonts/view/proxima-nova" target="_blank">Proxima Nova</a> and fallback to Arial Nova or other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sans-serif" target="_blank">sans serif fonts.</a></p>
<p>Then I cleaned up my CSS file to make the whole website <a href="https://medium.com/@Vincentxia77/what-is-mobile-first-design-why-its-important-how-to-make-it-7d3cf2e29d00" target="_blank">&ldquo;mobile-first&rdquo;.</a>
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="now-playing-station-pages">Now Playing Station Pages</h1>
<p>The tune-in or now playing page received most of the update. I&rsquo;ve broken some of them below:</p>
<h2 id="back-button">Back Button</h2>
<p>The back button got a lot of love with some logic. At first, the button always takes you to the home (main) page with the <code>&lt;a&gt;</code> tag attribute <code>href=&quot;/&quot;</code>.</p>
<p>Now, it&rsquo;s got a javascript code that checks for an open navigation menu, and whether the history came from the tunein.rpnradio.com domain.</p>
<pre><code>function goBack() {
  if (isNavOpen) {
    closeNav();
  }
  else if (document.referrer == "") {
    window.location.href = "https://tunein.rpnradio.com/";
  }
  else {
    window.history.back();
  }
}; </code></pre>
<p>This logic was finalized when I opened a page link on my iPhone then the back button took me to the previous page - other site.</p>
<p>Now the back button takes you to home page when started with a station page.</p>
<h2 id="navigation-menu">Navigation Menu</h2>
<p>The station pages got a navigation menu that resembles the home page. This is to give the listener a continuous audio stream playback whilst needing to change a station.</p>
<p>Note: The navigation drawer will not work on browser back button - as I learned with other sites. The browser just simply go back to the previous page.
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="security">Security</h1>
<p>The website was also SSL-enabled - <a href="https://www.websecurity.digicert.com/security-topics/https-everywhere" target="_blank">HTTPS Everywhere.</a></p>
<p>This also means that the old stream URLs will not work. Thankfully, the audio servers have secured stream URLs for secure websites.
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="open-graph-metadata">Open Graph Metadata</h1>
<p>Social Media sites are the places where websites get the most referrers. So having metadata for them not just makes the website Facebook- or Twitter-friendly but it is a great addition to how it would look like when shared.</p>
<p>Making the images took waaaaay longer than I expected. I decided to add 3 mockup devices that shows the website on these devices. You can see the share preview below:</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Facebook Open Graph Preview</em></figcaption>
<br/>

<figcaption><em>Twitter Open Graph Preview</em></figcaption>
</figure>
Creating the metadata tags was made easy by using <a href="https://metatags.io/" target="_blank">Metatags.io</a>.
<br/>
<br/>
<h1 id="site-icons">Site Icons</h1>
<p>I went on to also update the website&rsquo;s favicons, to differentiate tunein to the news website. It now has the Android app icon below:</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><em>Website Favicon</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="google-ads">Google Ads</h1>
<p>I replaced the part suggesting other methods to tunein (Zeno app, Radio Garden and our native Android app) with a Google Auto ad.</p>
<p>We all hate ads but this is the only modest way to profit for most websites.
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="htaccess-to-remove-html">.htaccess to Remove .html</h1>
<p>I finally made it to work, shorten the address for site navigation. Instead of showing the full file name: <pre><small>tunein.rpnradio.com/batac.html</small></pre>
Some rules were added to the .htaccess file to make it <pre><small>tunein.rpnradio.com/batac</small></pre></p>
<p>.htaccess file:</p>
<pre><code>RewriteEngine On 
RewriteCond %{HTTPS} off 
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI} [L,R=301]

RewriteCond %{THE_REQUEST} /([^.]+)\.html [NC]
RewriteRule ^ /%1 [NC,L,R]
RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME}.html -f
RewriteRule ^ %{REQUEST_URI}.html [NC,L]
</code></pre>
<br/>
<h1 id="footer-finally">Footer Finally</h1>
<p>I added a subtle footer to the whole website. That&rsquo;s it. :)
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="final-words">Final Words</h1>
<p>This website is another medium for the company&rsquo;s aim for a greater reach by expanding to Digital Media. In addition to our native apps (which is available for Android - <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1&hl=en&gl=US" target="_blank">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031" target="_blank">Huawei App Gallery</a>), the website also serves a means for our audiences to access our stations' broadcast anytime and anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>You can visit the website here: <a href="https://tunein./rpnradio.com/" target="_blank">Tune In — RPN Radio.</a></p>
<p>You may also want to check my blog post about the RPN Radio App here:<br/><a href="/rpnradio-android/">RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android.</a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>ZIP Code PH for Android gets Dark Mode</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:17:22 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/zipcodeph-android.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="the-pandemic-and-night-owls">The Pandemic and Night Owls</h1>
<p>My app, ZIP Code PH, has been available on Google Play Store for more than a year now and because of the pandemic, more and more people are staying at home and are mostly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night_owl_(person)">night-owls</a>.</p>
<p>And app and software developers are now giving their projects dark mode - not just to follow accessibility standards but offer an option for people to reduce or avoid eye strain.</p>
<h1 id="heres-dark-mode-for-ya">Here&rsquo;s Dark Mode for ya</h1>
<p>So here I am, picking up again on coding (for my apps) and started giving some apps a dark flavor. It almost took me a month to develop and test since available Xamarin Forms documentation didn&rsquo;t suit my liking.</p>
<h1 id="quick-app-features">Quick App Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Toggle light and dark mode</li>
<li>Quick search Philippine ZIP codes</li>
<li>Favorite (Bookmark) selected ZIP codes for easy reference</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<p>See for yourself the light and dark mode for the app below.</p>
<figure class="image">

<span style="margin: 0 10px"></span>

<figcaption><em>ZIP Code PH - Main Menu</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<figure class="image">

<span style="margin: 0 10px"></span>

<figcaption><em>ZIP Code PH - List</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>I chose <code>#222222</code> as the background color for darkmode so it is easier in the eyes (at least for me and some design posts I read somewhere). If someone requests an option for a darker color, I&rsquo;d be glad to add it. (Themes, maybe? 🤔)</p>
<h1 id="make-me-happy">Make me happy</h1>
<p>Yes, please. Make me happy by downloading the app, write a review and give a rating of 5 stars. The app is available for Android, on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.zipcodeph">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103245343">Huawei App Gallery.</a></p>
<p>It is free to download, I hope you welcome ads that earns a me a little. Thank you and until next app!</p>
<p><a href='https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.zipcodeph&pcampaignid=pcampaignidMKT-Other-global-all-co-prtnr-py-PartBadge-Mar2515-1'></a></p>
<h1 id="looking-for-a-windows-10-version">Looking for a Windows 10 version?</h1>
<p>Check out <a href="/zipcodeph-new-ui/">this old blog post</a> about the Windows 10 app.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:25:58 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpnradio.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>This should just be a short post to promote and showcase this Android app I developed for my job.</p>
<h1 id="am-radio-in-your-pocket">AM Radio in your Pocket</h1>
<p>Choose from RPN&rsquo;s <a href="https://rpnradio.com/" target="_blank">(Radio Philippines Network)</a> 12 regional AM stations to tune into. Just connect to the internet and be updated to the latest news, talks, and enjoy some old and new tunes.</p>
<h1 id="development">Development</h1>
<p>I tried making this app using Xamarin.Forms but the new Android implementation of the media notification sucked a** that I made the app in pure <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide">Android Java code</a>.</p>
<h1 id="app-description">App Description</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>RPN&rsquo;s 12 radio stations are situated among the three major parts of the Philippines - in Luzon, we have DZRL Batac and DZBS Baguio that will give you the latest news, updates, music and other events happening in the North in Ilocano; and DZKI Iriga to offer them in Rinkonada Bikol and/or Bikolano. Next in Visayas, DYKC Cebu and DYKB Bacolod operates in the heart of Cebu City and neighboring Bacolod City, respectively. DYKC Cebu provides an programming format that will surely make all Cebuanos and Bisaya all around the world miss home. While DYKB Bacolod gives you the most important news and talkshows in Hiligaynon and/or Ilonggo. Lastly, Mindanao holds most of our stations : DXKS Surigao, DXKO Cagayan de Oro, DXDX General Santos, DXKP Pagadian, DXXX Zamboanga, and DXKT Davao.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<figure class="image">


<figcaption><em>RPN Radio App for Android</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="download">Download</h1>
<p>The app is available to download for <strong>FREE</strong> from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031">Huawei App Store.</a></p>
<p>The app will be available soon on iOS.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RPN Android App</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 03:02:48 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/rpn-android.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Hey hey, recently I branched out my C# and apps knowledge to create and actually port or make versions of my UWP apps to Android using Xamarin Forms.</p>
<p>Finally opt-in and registered to Google Play platform and chose RPN News &amp; Radio to the Store as the first app (under my registered dev name) to become publicly available.</p>
<p>Obviously, this is unofficial and not backed by my employers. I believe having this in the store is essential to expand the platforms reached by RPN.</p>
<p>Also, there are some adjustments I needed to learn in using Xamarin Forms, and had to merge several projects to create both the news and radio part of the app. Thanks to open source!</p>
<p>There are still bugs, I know, but help by checking the app <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.rpnradio" taget="_blank">here</a></p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
