<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Apps - Tag - Red David&#39;s Blog</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/apps/</link>
        <description>Apps - Tag - Red David&#39;s Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 22:02:34 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/apps/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>ZIP Code PH Gets Refreshed UI</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 22:02:34 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-new-ui/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image2.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Over these past few months, I have been checking on some fluent design concepts and app updates over Twitter and other design sites like, Dribbble, Behance, and even Medium. Also, I have been busy gaming and doing some reading on my spare time that I missed coding and updating some of my apps.
Then one time, I just found the urge to update it after seeing Michael West&rsquo;s concept layouts over Dribbble.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Your Phone Tray V2</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 21:18:31 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/your-phone-tray-v2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/featured-image.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Your Phone Tray UWP app just got updated.
Version 2.0 brings few UI changes, some improvements and a breaking change.
Improvements To improve the app, I updated the tray icon context menu to show that it should be running on Startup (see Task Manager Start up) You can also see a new menu item Enable Ctrl+Y Hotkey. If enabled, the app silently picks up the Ctrl+Y shortcut to open Your Phone app.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RPN Android App</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 03:02:48 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/rpn-android-app/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/rpn-android.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Hey hey, recently I branched out my C# and apps knowledge to create and actually port or make versions of my UWP apps to Android using Xamarin Forms.
Finally opt-in and registered to Google Play platform and chose RPN News &amp; Radio to the Store as the first app (under my registered dev name) to become publicly available.
Obviously, this is unofficial and not backed by my employers. I believe having this in the store is essential to expand the platforms reached by RPN.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RF Tools Gets Multi-Window Support</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rftools-gets-multi-window-support/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 15:47:52 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/rftools-gets-multi-window-support/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/rftools.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>UWP SDK recently released a new support for Multi-windowing.
Then I though of which of my apps should I implement this with, there&rsquo;s nothing better than RF Tools, a calculator app for engineers and enthusiasts of radio frequency.
This should improve the user&rsquo;s experience by doing multiple calculations visible at once; to compare and serve as a history.
You can download the app here]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RPN News &amp; Radio Gets a New UI</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/new-ui-rpnradio/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 15:28:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/new-ui-rpnradio/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/rpn-newui.jpg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>A quite small update to fix and improve the overall UI of the app. Adding some fluent design, new font and smoother experience.
You can download RPN News &amp; Radio for Windows 10 app here]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
