<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Apps - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/apps/</link>
        <description>Apps - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:15:36 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/apps/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>RPN Radio UI Overhaul</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-ui-overhaul/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:15:36 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-ui-overhaul/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpnradio-ui.jpeg" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Browsing Instagram on my account now floods me with several UI/UX tips and practices, making me inspired to update and retouch my apps with some latest trends in mobile designs.</p>
<h1 id="old-look">Old Look</h1>
<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at what the app looked like before the update:</p>
<figure class="image">


<figcaption><em>Old UI</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>Though it looked intuitive - with just two simple steps: 1) Launch app, 2) Select station and Listen; the main page does not give the user context on what the app does, which raise this question:</p>
<p><strong><em>What am I supposed to do?</em></strong></p>
<h2 id="menu-list">Menu List</h2>
<p>At first glance of a first-time user, the stations list does NOT show that it is &ldquo;clickable&rdquo;. So the first UI update was to change the 4x3 grid to a simple list.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Station Menu Item Before and After</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>This subtle change provides the user a hint of &ldquo;click me&rdquo; by giving the list item a design of a button. It also gave a space for the station&rsquo;s detail to be added - station&rsquo;s location and live/offline status.</p>
<h2 id="header-and-controls">Header and Controls</h2>
<p>Ok, this area will look crammed especially on small-screen devices. Before this update though, I repositioned the buttons below the controls and were still crammed. This update allowed the horizontal list to be scrolled.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Header & Controls Before and After</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>I also changed the text that shows the current stations into a simpler one and updated the share icon.</p>
<h2 id="new-font">New Font</h2>
<p>I like <a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/Poppins" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Poppins</a>.
<br></p>
<h1 id="about">About</h1>
<p>Besides the UI updates mentioned above, I added an &ldquo;About&rdquo; page. It is a simple about and external links of RPN.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>About page</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="roadmap">Roadmap</h1>
<p>These are my to-do list for the app, which we will see soon on future updates:</p>
<ul>
<li>No internet connection status</li>
<li>Bottom player controls (Priority)</li>
<li>App-aware sharing</li>
<li>Rate and review prompt</li>
<li>Links to station email/messaging</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="downloads">Downloads</h1>
<p>As always, the app is still available for Android and (REALLY) soon for iOS.</p>
<p>Google Play Store: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1</a></p>
<p>Huawei App Gallery: <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031</a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>App Landing Page for ZIP Code PH</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-applandingpage/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 02:21:44 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-applandingpage/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/zipcodeph-applanding.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Now that ZIP Code PH is available for both Android and iOS, I wanted to build a landing page for it.</p>
<h1 id="inspiration">Inspiration</h1>
<p>I viewed some designs online and found inspiration from <a href="https://get-thrive.app/" target="_blank">Thrive</a>, which I never heard of - thanks anyway!</p>
<h1 id="launch-and-land">Launch and Land</h1>
<p>The webpage is available <a href="https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-app" target="_blank">HERE</a>. The page is still a link to my website but will soon acquire a domain for it soon. Also, the page is still a basic design but complete with the download links, which I will improve soon.</p>
<p>Will keep you updated!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Tune In RPN Radio Update</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/tunein-update/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 20:30:09 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/tunein-update/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpn-tunein.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>I updated the tune-in website for RPN. This post will detail the changes, what&rsquo;s new or removed, and how the update went.</p>
<h1 id="mainpage-and-mobile-first-design">MainPage and Mobile-First Design</h1>
<p>The main page remains got a few changes, starting with the font face and size. Before the update, the font family forced to check for <a href="https://www.marksimonson.com/fonts/view/proxima-nova" target="_blank">Proxima Nova</a> and fallback to Arial Nova or other <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sans-serif" target="_blank">sans serif fonts.</a></p>
<p>Then I cleaned up my CSS file to make the whole website <a href="https://medium.com/@Vincentxia77/what-is-mobile-first-design-why-its-important-how-to-make-it-7d3cf2e29d00" target="_blank">&ldquo;mobile-first&rdquo;.</a>
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="now-playing-station-pages">Now Playing Station Pages</h1>
<p>The tune-in or now playing page received most of the update. I&rsquo;ve broken some of them below:</p>
<h2 id="back-button">Back Button</h2>
<p>The back button got a lot of love with some logic. At first, the button always takes you to the home (main) page with the <code>&lt;a&gt;</code> tag attribute <code>href=&quot;/&quot;</code>.</p>
<p>Now, it&rsquo;s got a javascript code that checks for an open navigation menu, and whether the history came from the tunein.rpnradio.com domain.</p>
<pre><code>function goBack() {
  if (isNavOpen) {
    closeNav();
  }
  else if (document.referrer == "") {
    window.location.href = "https://tunein.rpnradio.com/";
  }
  else {
    window.history.back();
  }
}; </code></pre>
<p>This logic was finalized when I opened a page link on my iPhone then the back button took me to the previous page - other site.</p>
<p>Now the back button takes you to home page when started with a station page.</p>
<h2 id="navigation-menu">Navigation Menu</h2>
<p>The station pages got a navigation menu that resembles the home page. This is to give the listener a continuous audio stream playback whilst needing to change a station.</p>
<p>Note: The navigation drawer will not work on browser back button - as I learned with other sites. The browser just simply go back to the previous page.
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="security">Security</h1>
<p>The website was also SSL-enabled - <a href="https://www.websecurity.digicert.com/security-topics/https-everywhere" target="_blank">HTTPS Everywhere.</a></p>
<p>This also means that the old stream URLs will not work. Thankfully, the audio servers have secured stream URLs for secure websites.
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="open-graph-metadata">Open Graph Metadata</h1>
<p>Social Media sites are the places where websites get the most referrers. So having metadata for them not just makes the website Facebook- or Twitter-friendly but it is a great addition to how it would look like when shared.</p>
<p>Making the images took waaaaay longer than I expected. I decided to add 3 mockup devices that shows the website on these devices. You can see the share preview below:</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Facebook Open Graph Preview</em></figcaption>
<br/>

<figcaption><em>Twitter Open Graph Preview</em></figcaption>
</figure>
Creating the metadata tags was made easy by using <a href="https://metatags.io/" target="_blank">Metatags.io</a>.
<br/>
<br/>
<h1 id="site-icons">Site Icons</h1>
<p>I went on to also update the website&rsquo;s favicons, to differentiate tunein to the news website. It now has the Android app icon below:</p>
<figure>

<figcaption><em>Website Favicon</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="google-ads">Google Ads</h1>
<p>I replaced the part suggesting other methods to tunein (Zeno app, Radio Garden and our native Android app) with a Google Auto ad.</p>
<p>We all hate ads but this is the only modest way to profit for most websites.
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="htaccess-to-remove-html">.htaccess to Remove .html</h1>
<p>I finally made it to work, shorten the address for site navigation. Instead of showing the full file name: <pre><small>tunein.rpnradio.com/batac.html</small></pre>
Some rules were added to the .htaccess file to make it <pre><small>tunein.rpnradio.com/batac</small></pre></p>
<p>.htaccess file:</p>
<pre><code>RewriteEngine On 
RewriteCond %{HTTPS} off 
RewriteRule ^(.*)$ https://%{HTTP_HOST}%{REQUEST_URI} [L,R=301]

RewriteCond %{THE_REQUEST} /([^.]+)\.html [NC]
RewriteRule ^ /%1 [NC,L,R]
RewriteCond %{REQUEST_FILENAME}.html -f
RewriteRule ^ %{REQUEST_URI}.html [NC,L]
</code></pre>
<br/>
<h1 id="footer-finally">Footer Finally</h1>
<p>I added a subtle footer to the whole website. That&rsquo;s it. :)
<br/>
<br/></p>
<h1 id="final-words">Final Words</h1>
<p>This website is another medium for the company&rsquo;s aim for a greater reach by expanding to Digital Media. In addition to our native apps (which is available for Android - <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1&hl=en&gl=US" target="_blank">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031" target="_blank">Huawei App Gallery</a>), the website also serves a means for our audiences to access our stations' broadcast anytime and anywhere in the world.</p>
<p>You can visit the website here: <a href="https://tunein./rpnradio.com/" target="_blank">Tune In — RPN Radio.</a></p>
<p>You may also want to check my blog post about the RPN Radio App here:<br/><a href="/rpnradio-android/">RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android.</a></p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Developing for Apple Soon</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/developing-for-apple-soon/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:40:14 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/developing-for-apple-soon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/appstore.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="apple-user---me">Apple User -&gt; Me</h1>
<p>Yes, I gave in to use an Apple device. Well, I&rsquo;ve tried an iPhone XS before, and I must admit, having a device with software dedicated to its hardware is chef&rsquo;s kiss. That&rsquo;s what I liked about Apple, the hardware and software work along each other, and like most people, the price-tag for their phones held me back until December.</p>
<p>I <em>loaned</em> for an iPhone 11 since the iPhone 12 is expensive and I like the 11&rsquo;s grip instead of the sharp edges of the new design. I got a yellow one since the black sold out. Then I realized black, though very simple, is such a generic color that it doesn&rsquo;t stand out as a phone&rsquo;s color and I&rsquo;ve had too many black phones before.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Yellow iPhone 11</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="developing-for-ios-soon">Developing for iOS soon</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;m excited to learn new things and finally applying the cross-platform capabilities of <a href="https://dotnet.microsoft.com/apps/xamarin/xamarin-forms">Xamarin.Forms</a> which I have used in some of my Android apps and it&rsquo;s <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/tour-of-csharp/">C#</a>. I also want to check out native code from Apple, <a href="https://developer.apple.com/xcode/swiftui/">SwiftUI</a>.</p>
<p>Developing for Apple is quite costly, that you need to own a Mac (or rent online) and ₱4450 ($99) for an individual to publish to the App Store. And it is YEARLY.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>iOS 14 App Library (is that TikTok? 😅)</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>So, to test things out, I would be putting my app <a href="/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/">ZIP Code PH</a> on the App Store and might set a (very very small) price to support this costly Apple environment 😂.</p>
<h1 id="for-the-meantime">For the meantime&hellip;</h1>
<p>Go ahead and check out my apps on the <a href="ms-windows-store:publisher?name=Red David">Windows 10 Store</a> and <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/dev?id=5465762079490576029">Google Play Store</a> both under Red David.</p>
<p>See you soon!</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>ZIP Code PH for Android gets Dark Mode</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:17:22 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-android-dark-mode/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/zipcodeph-android.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><h1 id="the-pandemic-and-night-owls">The Pandemic and Night Owls</h1>
<p>My app, ZIP Code PH, has been available on Google Play Store for more than a year now and because of the pandemic, more and more people are staying at home and are mostly <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Night_owl_(person)">night-owls</a>.</p>
<p>And app and software developers are now giving their projects dark mode - not just to follow accessibility standards but offer an option for people to reduce or avoid eye strain.</p>
<h1 id="heres-dark-mode-for-ya">Here&rsquo;s Dark Mode for ya</h1>
<p>So here I am, picking up again on coding (for my apps) and started giving some apps a dark flavor. It almost took me a month to develop and test since available Xamarin Forms documentation didn&rsquo;t suit my liking.</p>
<h1 id="quick-app-features">Quick App Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Toggle light and dark mode</li>
<li>Quick search Philippine ZIP codes</li>
<li>Favorite (Bookmark) selected ZIP codes for easy reference</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<p>See for yourself the light and dark mode for the app below.</p>
<figure class="image">

<span style="margin: 0 10px"></span>

<figcaption><em>ZIP Code PH - Main Menu</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<figure class="image">

<span style="margin: 0 10px"></span>

<figcaption><em>ZIP Code PH - List</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>I chose <code>#222222</code> as the background color for darkmode so it is easier in the eyes (at least for me and some design posts I read somewhere). If someone requests an option for a darker color, I&rsquo;d be glad to add it. (Themes, maybe? 🤔)</p>
<h1 id="make-me-happy">Make me happy</h1>
<p>Yes, please. Make me happy by downloading the app, write a review and give a rating of 5 stars. The app is available for Android, on <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.zipcodeph">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103245343">Huawei App Gallery.</a></p>
<p>It is free to download, I hope you welcome ads that earns a me a little. Thank you and until next app!</p>
<p><a href='https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=xyz.reddvid.zipcodeph&pcampaignid=pcampaignidMKT-Other-global-all-co-prtnr-py-PartBadge-Mar2515-1'></a></p>
<h1 id="looking-for-a-windows-10-version">Looking for a Windows 10 version?</h1>
<p>Check out <a href="/zipcodeph-new-ui/">this old blog post</a> about the Windows 10 app.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RPN Radio: Streaming App for Android</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 01:25:58 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rpnradio-android/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/rpnradio.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>This should just be a short post to promote and showcase this Android app I developed for my job.</p>
<h1 id="am-radio-in-your-pocket">AM Radio in your Pocket</h1>
<p>Choose from RPN&rsquo;s <a href="https://rpnradio.com/" target="_blank">(Radio Philippines Network)</a> 12 regional AM stations to tune into. Just connect to the internet and be updated to the latest news, talks, and enjoy some old and new tunes.</p>
<h1 id="development">Development</h1>
<p>I tried making this app using Xamarin.Forms but the new Android implementation of the media notification sucked a** that I made the app in pure <a href="https://developer.android.com/guide">Android Java code</a>.</p>
<h1 id="app-description">App Description</h1>
<blockquote>
<p>RPN&rsquo;s 12 radio stations are situated among the three major parts of the Philippines - in Luzon, we have DZRL Batac and DZBS Baguio that will give you the latest news, updates, music and other events happening in the North in Ilocano; and DZKI Iriga to offer them in Rinkonada Bikol and/or Bikolano. Next in Visayas, DYKC Cebu and DYKB Bacolod operates in the heart of Cebu City and neighboring Bacolod City, respectively. DYKC Cebu provides an programming format that will surely make all Cebuanos and Bisaya all around the world miss home. While DYKB Bacolod gives you the most important news and talkshows in Hiligaynon and/or Ilonggo. Lastly, Mindanao holds most of our stations : DXKS Surigao, DXKO Cagayan de Oro, DXDX General Santos, DXKP Pagadian, DXXX Zamboanga, and DXKT Davao.</p>
</blockquote>
<h1 id="screenshots">Screenshots</h1>
<figure class="image">


<figcaption><em>RPN Radio App for Android</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<h1 id="download">Download</h1>
<p>The app is available to download for <strong>FREE</strong> from <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rpnradio.radiov1">Google Play Store</a> and <a href="https://appgallery.huawei.com/#/app/C103076031">Huawei App Store.</a></p>
<p>The app will be available soon on iOS.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>RF Tools Gets Multi-Window Support</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/rftools-gets-multi-window-support/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 15:47:52 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/rftools-gets-multi-window-support/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/rftools.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>UWP SDK recently released a new support for Multi-windowing.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Then I though of which of my apps should I implement this with, there&rsquo;s nothing better than RF Tools, a calculator app for engineers and enthusiasts of radio frequency.</p>
<p>This should improve the user&rsquo;s experience by doing multiple calculations visible at once; to compare and serve as a history.</p>
<p></p>
<p></p>
<p>You can <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/rf-tools/9nblggh41btt" target="_blank">download the app here</a></p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
