<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>YouTube on David Ballesteros</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/youtube/</link>
        <description>Recent content in YouTube on David Ballesteros</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 22:26:48 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Unlocked: 1K Followers</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/unlocked-1k-followers/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 22:26:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://reddavid.me/unlocked-1k-followers/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://reddavid.me/images/feat/1k-followers.png" alt="Featured image of post Unlocked: 1K Followers" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all, thank you so much to all who stayed, watched, and enjoyed my content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was on May 26th that we finally got to a thousand following after a year of starting to be a Gaming Video Creator on Facebook. The stream felt like another day of chill streaming by playing a couple of hours of Minecraft. It was quite overwhelming for a small-time (and not full-time) streamer like me but thanks to my cousins and og supporters for helping me out in the chat and Discord server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/1k-achievement.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;1K followers achievement custom&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deldailydel-nightly-streams&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Daily&lt;/del&gt; Nightly Streams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that there&amp;rsquo;s that 1K following behind me, I will pursue to stream on a daily basis, even a short one because honestly, I miss talking and updating with them. I will also continue to improve my stream quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-minecraft-hello&#34;&gt;Not Minecraft, Hello?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minecraft is a really popular game we all know that, and most of my followers were because of the game. I do not expect everyone to like me playing variety of games but I still hope most could support me when I come back playing other types of games. Although, I would still join our SMP server if I fail to stream Minecraft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;twitchyoutube-switch&#34;&gt;Twitch/YouTube Switch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I have been thinking of switching to either one, why? First, Twitch have several audience interaction which I have been using when I watch my favorite streamers there like, watch points, play with viewers, etc and you can watch on app minimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://reddavid.me/images/twitch-minimized.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Watch Twitch Videos Minimized&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Watch Twitch Videos Minimized&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While YouTube had a better chat system, but chat highlights and audience interactions are better - with chatbots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I held back these thoughts before since I did start my Facebook page a long time and gained a few followers. I just hoped if I made up my mind to switch, we can determine the real supporters. Maybe?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this blog post. Thank you again for visiting my website and you can catch up on my Gaming Videos on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fb.gg/RedDavidGaming&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Facebook Gaming&lt;/a&gt; and follower me there. You can also follow me on my socials: @reddvid&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
