<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>SMP - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/smp/</link>
        <description>SMP - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 02:52:30 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/smp/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Streaming Again &amp; Minecraft SMP Season 2</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/minecraft-smp-season-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 02:52:30 &#43;0800</pubDate><dc:creator>David</dc:creator><guid>https://reddavid.me/minecraft-smp-season-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/mc-smp-s02.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Rejoice! My more-than-a-month-long hiatus finally came to an end - I&rsquo;m back to streaming video games in Facebook Gaming. In just 2 days, I&rsquo;ve managed to garner a whopping 8+ hours as compared before.</p>
<p>This also means that I am back to relieving some stress thru my beloved game Minecraft, (Survival Mode).</p>
<h1 id="first-world">First World?</h1>
<p>The first server I rented became <strike>toxic</strike> unenjoyable after a few months after opening it into the public - NO it&rsquo;s not because of the new players, but because the server was technically &ldquo;DONE&rdquo; by having usable XP farms, stripped mines, food source, and other auto AFK farms. Which meant that new players have nothing more to do but mess around most of the time.</p>
<p>I tried to reload the server with a new world but it kept corrupting upto the point that I reverted it back to the older (toxic) world. And I stopped playing less and less.</p>
<h1 id="refreshed-and-new-season-two">Refreshed and New? SEASON TWO</h1>
<p>Yes, after I decided to stream again, I hastily rented a new server and invite some of my OG followers to play with me. As of now, the world is still peaceful and managed to invite more players in hoping we can live happily in the upcoming days.</p>
<p>Unlike before, the server is now Offline-mode, meaning that non-Mojang accounts can now join - be CAREFUL though, WE CAN STILL <strong>BAN</strong> YOU.</p>
<h2 id="wanna-join">Wanna join?</h2>
<p>Head over to our Discord server for the rules and guidelines, and for the Server IP.</p>
<p><a href="https://discord.gg/rKnJb4J" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red David Discord Server</a></p>
<h2 id="get-your-own-minecraft-server">Get Your Own Minecraft Server</h2>
<p>Hosted by Shockbyte, cheap and reliable servers are offered for you. Check them out <a href="https://bit.ly/ShockByteMC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</p>
<h1 id="hello-1k-followers">Hello 1K Followers</h1>
<p>I have been aiming to reach followers before the year 2020 ends but I failed to do so, much more that I stopped streaming for more than a month.</p>
<p>Now with regained confidence, I am on the path to reach that goal while improving my streaming. So head over to my <a href="https://fb.gg/RedDavidGG" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook Gaming Page</a> and see if you like me to gain a Follow!</p>
<h1 id="looking-for-support">✨Looking for Support</h1>
<p>Also, I tried streaming mobile games now and then but the current setup is not suited for it. I am slowly building funds to get the setup for mobile games too.</p>
<p>Receiving stars during my live streams are very much appreciated by placing your names on my Starwall here: <a href="https://reddavid.me/starwall" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Star-senders Wall</a></p>
<p>Buy me Coffee: <a href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/RedDavid" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.buymeacoffee.com/RedDavid</a></p>
<p>PayPal: <a href="https://paypal.me/reddvid/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://paypal.me/reddvid</a></p>
<p>Tip through StreamElements: <a href="https://streamelements.com/reddavidgaming/tip" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://streamelements.com/reddavidgaming/tip</a></p>
<p>GCash 🇵🇭 : 09760226611</p>
<p>Visit my helpful links: <a href="https://reddavid.me/links" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red David Links</a></p>
<p><a href="https://reddavid.me/zipcodeph-app/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Download</a> my ZIP Code PH app</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
