<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Samsung - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</title>
        <link>https://reddavid.me/tags/samsung/</link>
        <description>Samsung - Tag - Red David | Coding, Tech, Gaming, and Music</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 01:09:00 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reddavid.me/tags/samsung/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Upgrade! Samsung 970 EVO Plus</title>
    <link>https://reddavid.me/samsung-evo/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 01:09:00 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://reddavid.me/samsung-evo/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/feat/970-evo-plus.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Here we go again folks! Another PC upgrade, this time we take our storage to the next level.</p>
<h1 id="top-player">Top Player</h1>
<p>I just bought a Samsung 970 EVO Plus, 1TB for my &ldquo;coding needs&rdquo;. I recently experience a throttle while using my current XPG 500GB - I have been using some Virtual Machines lately to test out some things, and the SSD space gets loaded up quickly.</p>
<p>The SSD costs me around US$100 and failed to get a cheaper one since I am not paying the whole price - again, I got this for credit. 😅</p>
<h1 id="samsung-why">Samsung, why?</h1>
<p>Samsung has been the top brand for SSDs and I can say this myself since personally, I used an 860 EVO in the past for my laptop. And even though my current XPG SSD does it&rsquo;s job, I needed an storage upgrade and it&rsquo;s time to get this one.</p>
<p>The technical specs and comparison is available in the internet which you can visit on PCWorld, <a href="https://www.pcworld.com/article/3334876/samsung-970-evo-plus-review-samsungs-entry-level-nvme-ssd-is-faster-and-cheaper.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Samsung 970 EVO Plus review</a></p>
<h1 id="take-a-look">Take a Look</h1>
<p>I forgot to take pictures to avoid the SSD from picking up some static from my desk mat. But I did take a picture of the box before installing it on the system.</p>
<figure class="image">

<figcaption><em>Samsung 970 EVO Plus</em></figcaption>

<figcaption><em>Taskbar</em></figcaption>
</figure>
<br/>
<p>This is not to flaunt the things I have, I&rsquo;m just trying to share my thoughts and share which can help my daily activities like coding, and file and graphics processing.</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
